<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Technically Tim</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://tim.purewhite.id.au/</id><updated>2015-02-21T00:00:00+10:00</updated><entry><title>Arduino wireless LiPo monitoring</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2015/02/arduino-lipo-wireless-monitor/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-02-21T00:00:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2015-02-21:2015/02/arduino-lipo-wireless-monitor/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Crashed RC Car" src="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/images/2015/IMG_20150221_150813_edit.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the last few months, I've been getting back into electronics. It's really
not fair what's available now, that wasn't available when I was a kid!
Arduino's for a start are a very easy way to get into microcontrollers. And
with the Arduino scene has come lots of small electronic components for only a
few dollars each.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As part of a bigger project, I'm automating my RC car from my childhood. The
Taiyo Edge car was an awesome toy as a kid, with it's ability to flip over and
still keep driving. As a kid, I'd get a top of 10 minutes driving time out of
the NiCd battery. Now I'm lucky to get 5 minutes. So the first part of my
project is to put an Arduino onboard, with a LiPo battery, and a NRF24L01 to
communicate back to my other Arduino for monitoring the battery voltage. Later
I'll use the the Arduino to control the car as well.i&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After designign the circuit in Fritzing, I proceeded to solder components to a
protoboard with the Arduino Nano. I recently purchased a proper soldering
station, temperature controlled, and I'm really glad I did. I wish I had one as
a kid. No more waiting for the iron to heat up, it's ready in 10 seconds or
less. Soon I have the Arduino Nano wirelessly reporting the LiPo's voltage back
to me, and wire it up to the car. The LiPo I got was a 7.2V 1000mAh pack,
that's about 1/2 the size of the NiCd that was in the car. Plenty of room for
it, and even with the lower voltage it drives the car well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We took the car outside for it's first test run on a LiPo, and was pleasently
surprised with how well it performed, and how long it went for! We had about 20
minutes driving time before we called it quits, and that was mostly due to the
rain, and because Nathan had crashed the car into the trampoline cracking the
shell. The voltage measurements continue to stream back to my computer inside,
which I monitored via my phone. By the time we stop, I still had plenty of
voltage to continue driving, and the LiPo hadn't warmed up at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next step is to remove the RC circuitry, work out what I can use, and then
replace it with circuitry that I can control via the Arduino. I also have some
Ultrasonic sensors for obsticle avoidance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Receiving Arduino Uno" src="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/images/2015/IMG_20150221_151115_edit.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="arduino"></category><category term="electronics"></category><category term="LiPo"></category><category term="nrf24l01"></category></entry><entry><title>Wordpress to Pelican</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2014/03/wordpress-to-pelican/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2014-03-29T00:00:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2014-03-29:2014/03/wordpress-to-pelican/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been awhile since I last blogged. Since then, I've started a full time job
as a Systems Administrator. This means I have less time for maintaining my own
servers. So I've finally taken the plunge migrating some of the more static
sites to static. For example this Technical blog will now be a static site. 
This doesn't mean it won't get updated, this just means that it's generated with
a static generator instead of being generated dynamically when someone views the
page. This results in lower server load, as it doesn't need PHP running, or a 
database. It results in faster page loads. It results in a more secure server as
it's just running a webserver and no web application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe it results in blogs that are more focused on content than on the web
application that displays the content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've chosen to use &lt;a href="https://github.com/getpelican/pelican"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;, mostly
because I've enjoyed learning Python over the last year, and this gives me 
another excuse to play with some Python. I'm also more comfortable in Python than
some of the other options so this allows me to hack away on the code if I want to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the current lack of comments on the blog. I'm still thinking of the best
way to handle that. I may just put a Google+ comments plugin on, as I really
don't like Disqus. I may also just not put dynamic comments on and use Github issues
for discussing posts as some others have done.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="wordpress"></category><category term="pelican"></category></entry><entry><title>"Windows" is full of bloat</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2013/05/windows-is-full-of-bloat/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-18T17:18:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2013-05-18:2013/05/windows-is-full-of-bloat/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been some time since I've had to do some work on a Windows
computer, in particular lots of software installs and uninstalls to
cleanup a slow computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now before you jump the gun, I'm not talking about Windows the operating
system being full of bloat, although it may be. I'm also not talking
about the bloat that comes installed on OEM installs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I am talking about, is how so much third party free windows
software is full of bloat. Just about every installer now wants to
install another piece of software with the piece you downloaded, ether a
toolbar or another "great" piece of software they recommend to you. And
then when you uninstall a piece of software, just about every piece of
software then insist on opening a webpage saying how sorry they are that
you uninstalled the software and would you please do this 5 minute
survey telling them why blah blah blah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even my favourite antivirus Avast has started doing it. First, the
installer has jumped from 20Mb a few years ago to over 100Mb now. And
now when you install it, if you aren't watching out it'll try and
install Google Drive, and once it is installed it keeps popping up
asking you to install the great security extension for chrome, blah blah
blah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What ever happened to nice free software that wasn't packed full of
bloat, and that let you install and uninstall just that software that
you asked for without trying to push other software on you? I'll happily
keep my Linux world, where software does what you ask, and nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you live in the Windows world, seriously, I think it's well past
time to get out, but you can still get out now!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bloat"></category><category term="windows"></category></entry><entry><title>Wordpress Server Maintenance</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2013/04/wordpress-server-maintenance/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-04-25T14:00:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2013-04-25:2013/04/wordpress-server-maintenance/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Wow. Somehow I missed when this amazing tool was released. &lt;a href="http://wp-cli.org/" title="wp-cli"&gt;wp-cli&lt;/a&gt;.
Just wow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a bunch of scripts I use to keep all the Wordpress installs up to
date on my server, it finds all the installs, then it downloads the
latest version, checks each install for the installed version and
updates them by extracting the files correctly, ensuring user
permissions etc. However, that only keeps the core updated, I still need
to rely on all my customers to keep their plugins updated. This is ok,
except when a plugin has a security issue and needs to be updated ASAP.
Recently, we had just that situation with the WP-Super-Cache plugin. So
I modified my scripts, and now they update that particular plugin. But
it would be a pain to write a script that updated every plugin, so I'm
stuck logging into a number of sites I maintain, updating all the
plugins regularly, and then hoping for the sites that the customer
maintains, they do the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter, &lt;a href="http://wp-cli.org/" title="wp-cli"&gt;wp-cli&lt;/a&gt;. The tool I've been dreaming of for a long time.
Simply install, then using the basic structure of my script (the part
that finds all installs, verifies they are valid installs, and executes
commands as the user who owns the install), I can now run any of the
awesome &lt;a href="http://wp-cli.org/" title="wp-cli"&gt;wp-cli&lt;/a&gt; commands on all the sites I host! Server maintenance
just got a whole lot easier (as long as no plugin updates break things)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the really lazy, here is my code for updating all plugins, using the
wp-cli scripts. It uses sudo, so make sure you know what you are doing.
You may also have to tweak how locate finds things, as by default it
won't show you files you can't access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="c"&gt;#!/bin/bash&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="c"&gt;# Just find all installs and try and run tools in them&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c"&gt;# find wp-config.php files&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;SAVEIFS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$IFS&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;IFS&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; -en &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;\n\b&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;installs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;locate -r wp-config.php&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; conffile in &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$installs&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="c"&gt;# goto root wp dir as user&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nv"&gt;wpdir&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;dirname &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$conffile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nb"&gt;pushd&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$wpdir&lt;/span&gt; &amp;gt; /dev/null &lt;span class="o"&gt;||&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;exit&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="nb"&gt;    echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;Checking &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$wpdir&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt;...&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="c"&gt;## Check we actually have a wordpress install&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;[[&lt;/span&gt; ! -f &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;wp-includes/version.php&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;||&lt;/span&gt; ! -f &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$conffile&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;]]&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;then&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$wpdir&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s2"&gt; doesn&amp;#39;t appear to be a wordpress install, skipping...&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="k"&gt;continue&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="k"&gt;fi&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="c"&gt;# Get username for tool&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nv"&gt;username&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;$(&lt;/span&gt;stat -c %U &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$conffile&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="c"&gt;# run tool commands&lt;/span&gt;
    sudo -u &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$username&lt;/span&gt; -- wp plugin update-all

    &lt;span class="nb"&gt;popd&lt;/span&gt; &amp;gt; /dev/null
&lt;span class="k"&gt;done&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="security"></category><category term="updates"></category><category term="wordpress"></category><category term="wp-cli"></category></entry><entry><title>Submitting Empty Checkboxes when in Array</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2012/09/submitting-empty-checkboxes-when-in-array/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-09-11T15:20:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2012-09-11:2012/09/submitting-empty-checkboxes-when-in-array/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In HTML, we often use a nice feature for POSTing a form, or submitting a
form, where we have lots of items the "same". In the Grase Hotspot
project, we have groups for example, and we can dynamically add and
delete groups, but need a complete form for each group with it's
settings. So we use an "array" to submit the values. Simple put, we have
a number of \&amp;lt;inputs&gt; with the same name, but with square brackets on
the end. i.e. \&amp;lt;input type="text" name="groupprice[]"/&gt;, and we have
multiples of these. Thanks to page ordering, we can have a number of
different arrays as well, and can associate all the group values
together thanks to their positions in each array.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this breaks when we are submitting checkboxes, because
unchecked checkboxes won't submit. When unchecked, they are a form
element that isn't successful, and only successful form elements are
submitted. That's fine, except we are relying on the array behaviour to
match elements together, and when a checkbox isn't submitted, it doesn't
even take up an array position, it's just absent, which means all
following checkboxes on the page are now in the wrong spot in the array
and not matched with the other arrays.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So normally when we submit input fields and some items have been left
blank, they still consume a spot in the array, like so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;array(4) {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;[0]=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;string(6) &amp;quot;Item 1&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;[1]=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;string(0) &amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;[2]=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;string(0) &amp;quot;&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;[3]=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;string(6) &amp;quot;Item 4&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;However, the checkboxes (which have a value on On normally when
checked), would appear like so (with Item numbers instead of "On" for
clarity)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="x"&gt;array(2) {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;[0]=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;string(6) &amp;quot;Item 1&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;[1]=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;string(6) &amp;quot;Item 4&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="x"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;There are solutions out there, however none work very well for dynamic
adding and creating "groups" of data, including checkboxes. Given that
the dynamic creation and deletion of those groups is with Javascript,
I've turned to a small javascript snippit to get it working. Hopefully
I'll find a nice way to have it fallback when javascript is disabled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found the solution I'm using at &lt;a href="http://www.dwright.us/?p=472"&gt;http://www.dwright.us/?p=472&lt;/a&gt; however
couldn't get it working well. A bit of fiddling and working on the
solution in the comments and I came up with the following snippit that
works nicely for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;document&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;ready&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kd"&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="c1"&gt;// do when submit is pressed&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="nx"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;form&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;submit&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kd"&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span class="nx"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;input:checkbox:not(:checked)&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;each&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="kd"&gt;function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;()&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class="nx"&gt;console&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;attr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;name&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;));&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class="nx"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;before&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;&amp;lt;input&amp;gt;&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;attr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;class&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;_temp&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;attr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;type&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;hidden&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;attr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;name&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nx"&gt;$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;this&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nx"&gt;attr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s1"&gt;&amp;#39;name&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)));&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class="c1"&gt;// .val(&amp;#39;off&amp;#39;));&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="p"&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;  
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="p"&gt;});&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;One of the main things I changed (once I made it work) was not having it
set the "extra" inputs to the value of "Off", but leaving them as an
empty value. This is because in my code I run the incoming arrays
through array_filter which removes all the empty ones (and maintains
the array indexes so the order and position is still there).&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="array"></category><category term="checkboxes"></category><category term="empty"></category><category term="HTML"></category><category term="submit"></category></entry><entry><title>When did 'Linux' start moving away from it's simplicity?</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2012/05/when-did-linux-start-moving-away-from-its-simplicity/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-08T19:46:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2012-05-08:2012/05/when-did-linux-start-moving-away-from-its-simplicity/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I had the joy of trying to change a users desktop environment from
Gnome, to Cinnamon, via ssh. At first I thought it would be easy, change
the default desktop environment in lightdm.conf and restart. Fail. Ok,
so where is a users desktop environment preference stored? .dmrc, or at
least I thought so. I even logged in with a brand new user and confirmed
that it saved the users desktop preference in \~/.dmrc. Except, if I
changed .dmrc for a user, it just got overwritten with the old contents
at their next automatic login. (Remember, ssh, so can't use the gui to
change what was selected in the lightdm login screen).&lt;br /&gt;
Wha?!!? Surely not a dconf/gconf setting somewhere. Search search
search. Still no luck. Eventually I discover a service called
"AccountsService" or something along that name. It stores the users
".dmrc" contents in /var/lib/AccountsService/users/ with a file for each
user, which believe it or not, can't be changed by the user! Arg! (And I
believe you need to kill accountsservice to be able to change the
contents of the file and have it actually honored, I tried just changing
it, but ended up changing it then rebooting to get it to work)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is stupidity! Have a daemon, that one of it's tasks is to tell the
"display manager" what the users preferred desktop environment
preference is, that stores it in a place the user can't change, without
talking to the daemon! Oh, and write the contents of that file out to
.dmrc at login, but don't bother reading from that file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing some more digging, AccountService is for querying and manipulating
user account information via D-Bus, essentially replacing the useradd,
usermod and userdel commands. I can't find a "homepage" for it, the
homepage listed is it's source code repo.
(&lt;a href="http://cgit.freedesktop.org/accountsservice/"&gt;http://cgit.freedesktop.org/accountsservice/&lt;/a&gt;)  (NB: Some more digging
finds this &lt;a href="http://www.freedesktop.org/wiki/Software/AccountsService"&gt;http://www.freedesktop.org/wiki/Software/AccountsService&lt;/a&gt; as
the homepage)&lt;br /&gt;
I personally don't mind D-Bus, it services its purposes, but here is an
instance where it looks like someone has gone to the trouble of writing
a piece of code, to complicate some that use to be a simple stat/open of
a file, that the user was in total control of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the record, lightdm will work without AccountsService, and I believe
then it will honor \~/.dmrc&lt;br /&gt;
Also, accountsservice isn't in Debian stable, but is in Debian testing,
and gdm3 and gnome depend on it. (So in other words Gnome3 depends on
it)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just don't understand why we need to reinvent the wheel, take
something that is so simple (and fits in the Unix "philosophies" of
everything is a file, and that file formats should be simple text based)
and turn it into something that user no longer has control over, for
something that sets their preference!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read
[http://blog.ngas.ch/archives/2011/12/13/the_destructive_desktop__mdash_linux_in_trouble/index.html][]for
some more thoughts on dbus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;http://blog.ngas.ch/archives/2011/12/13/the_destructive_desktop__mdash_linux_in_trouble/index.html%20
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="accountservice"></category><category term="accountsservice"></category><category term="dbus"></category><category term="Gnome3"></category><category term="Linux"></category><category term="simplicity"></category><category term="unix"></category></entry><entry><title>Belkin? Rtkit?</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/11/belkin-rtkit/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-11-05T12:10:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-11-05:2011/11/belkin-rtkit/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;While attempting to remotely debug a linux machine today, I was first
encountering a strange problem. Any process that took more than about
1/2 second to complete, would freeze. top, ps, lsmod, tail -f, the list
goes on. For example, trying to run dmesg and display it's output would
freeze, but dmesg into a file, and it would complete!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After much digging, I eventually found that rtkit (rtkit-daemon) is
constantly trying to make pulseaudio operate at realtime. In reality, we
don't need our audio to operate in realtime as most modern computers can
keep up with video playback just fine. For the few people we actually
want near real time audio (say, people recording multitrack stuff), then
they can enable it themselves. Disabling rtkit (actually, uninstalling
it as it appears to be started in dbus stuff), seems to have solved that
problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next problem was a strange DNS response. A dns request through the
Belkin modem, to this server (purewhite.id.au) would return 10.45.41.175
instead of 175.41.45.10. I know what reverse DNS is, but this is reverse
IP! Belkin is returning the ip in reverse!! (Or backwards if you
desire). A quick check reveals that this relatively new modem, hasn't
got any new firmware for it (and it's firmware is over 1 year old).
Apparently, someone else had this problem and belkin told them to just
hard code the ip's in your hosts file for the hosts that are being
returned wrong! I believe it was also a Belkin modem that would return
strange results when you did an AAAA request (ipv6).&lt;br /&gt;
So if you have a Belkin, maybe force your computer to use your ISP's
DNS servers directly, rather than the routers. (Or take it back to the
shop, because after all, it is faulty)&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="backwards ip"></category><category term="belkin"></category><category term="reverse ip"></category><category term="rtkit"></category></entry><entry><title>Nginx, PHP-FPM, Wordpress, Super Cache</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/10/nginx-php-fpm-wordpress-super-cache/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-10-24T11:37:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-10-24:2011/10/nginx-php-fpm-wordpress-super-cache/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So recently I've been exploring the alternative world of Nginx instead
of Apache, and PHP-FPM instead of mod_php. There are plenty of
tutorials on the net for getting all of this setup, however not that
many are up to date anymore for the Super Cache stuff. Hopefully what I
present here will be a more up to date config, that is also mostly
secure compare to a good number of ones on the net (to do with passing
non PHP files to the php interpreter).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, my Nginx config for this very blog.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;server&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="kn"&gt;server_name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;www.tim.purewhite.id.au&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class="kn"&gt;rewrite&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;^/(.*)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;http://tim.purewhite.id.au/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;permanent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;server&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="kn"&gt;server_name&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;tim.purewhite.id.au&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;static.tim.purewhite.id.au&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="kn"&gt;root&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;/home/tim/domains/tim.purewhite.id.au/public_html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="kn"&gt;access_log&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;/var/log/nginx/tim.purewhite.id.au_access_log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="kn"&gt;access_log&lt;/span&gt;  &lt;span class="s"&gt;/var/log/nginx/default.access.log&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;host_combined&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="c1"&gt;#access_log  /var/log/nginx/uri.log host_combined_uri;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="kn"&gt;error_log&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;/var/log/nginx/tim.purewhite.id.au_error_log&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="kn"&gt;index&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;index.php&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="kn"&gt;location&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;

        &lt;span class="kn"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$http_cookie&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;~&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="sr"&gt;&amp;quot;comment_author_|wordpress|wp-postpass_&amp;quot;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="kn"&gt;rewrite&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;^/(.*)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;/loggedin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;last&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="kn"&gt;try_files&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$uri&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="s"&gt;/wordpress/wp-content/cache/supercache/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$http_host/$uri/index.html&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$uri/&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="s"&gt;/index.php&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="kn"&gt;location&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;/loggedin&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="kn"&gt;internal&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="kn"&gt;rewrite&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;^/loggedin(.*)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$1&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;break&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="kn"&gt;try_files&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$uri&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$uri/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;/index.php&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;


    &lt;span class="kn"&gt;location&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;^~&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;/code&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="kn"&gt;proxy_set_header&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;Host&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$host&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="kn"&gt;proxy_set_header&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;X-Forwarded-Server&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$host&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="kn"&gt;proxy_set_header&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;X-Forwarded-Host&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$host&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="kn"&gt;proxy_set_header&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;X-Forwarded-For&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$proxy_add_x_forwarded_for&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="kn"&gt;proxy_pass&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;http://127.0.0.1:8080/code/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="kn"&gt;location&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;~&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="sr"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;\.(ico|css|js|gif|jpe?g|png)&lt;/span&gt;$ &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="kn"&gt;expires&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;1w&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="kn"&gt;break&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;



    &lt;span class="kn"&gt;fastcgi_intercept_errors&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="no"&gt;off&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="kn"&gt;location&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;~&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="sr"&gt;\.php&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="kn"&gt;try_files&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$uri&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;404&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="kn"&gt;include&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;fastcgi_params&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="kn"&gt;fastcgi_pass&lt;/span&gt;   &lt;span class="n"&gt;127.0.0.1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="mi"&gt;9002&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="kn"&gt;include&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;drop&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="p"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The first thing to notice is line 1-4. This simply redirects everyone
from www.tim.purewhite.id.au to tim.purewhite.id.au. Simple as that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next we define the server and the root document path. Still very
standard. Then we define access logs, for various reason I'm logging to
more than one place, but that'll change once everything is finished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Line 15 is boring, we just define the "index index.php" so that if you
access a directory it will load index.php or give you a 404 (which it
won't because of things further down).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now for the fun. Lines 19-21. These catch a logged in user and send them
on an internal redirect down to lines 28-32. This is so we don't serve
cached content to logged in users. That little snippit is thanks to a
post at &lt;a href="http://permalink.gmane.org/gmane.comp.web.nginx.english/15664"&gt;http://permalink.gmane.org/gmane.comp.web.nginx.english/15664&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, there was a problem in the rest of the code. Thanks to a post
at
&lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/support/topic/lack-of-nginx-support-from-wp-super-cache"&gt;http://wordpress.org/support/topic/lack-of-nginx-support-from-wp-super-cache&lt;/a&gt;
I realised we needed to test if the cache was being used or not. So I
added the extra logging and discovered it wasn't. I quickly worked out
what the problem was. The code at lines 22 - 25 had the middle 2 lines
swapped around. So "\$uri/" was before the supercache line. What this
mean was that it would try if the \$uri was a directory, and to load a
directory it would try index.php (due to the index line) and so would
end up loading wordpress through index.php. However, if we try the
supercache line first, we find the cache file and so don't need to load
indexes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And just like that, magic, it works! We use supercache files for normal
users, and if a cache file doesn't exist, we load wordpress like normal!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm also looking at how we run Nginx and PHP-FPM. I have heard of a few
ways, one being that root runs a Nginx as user nginx or nobody, and each
user runs their own Nginx which we proxy to from the main one. (And
users run their own PHP-FPM as well). This sounds like a lot of work,
very complicated, but yes, it gives you absolute security as only the
user can access his web docs and scripts, and everything runs as that
user. No one else's php process can load your config file to discover
your database passwords.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way of running it is with Nginx as a nginx/nobody/www-data user,
and each user run their own php-fpm but give the nginx/nobody/www-data
user read only access to the web directory. If done correctly, this can
actually be very secure. First, (as root) you chgrp all the files and
directories in the users doc root (htdocs, www, public_html etc) to the
user nginx will run as. Ideally, you also only allow them read access
(so `chmod g+rX,g-w -R public_html` will give them access to read,
but not write). You then set the gid bit on the directory; `chmod g+s
public_html` (and do this for any directories that already exist
underneath). Now any files the user creates underneath the public_html
dir will be readable to the nginx user, so nginx can serve static files.
Now running php-fpm as each user (I use php-fpm with a pool per user),
the php process can read all the files that user can, so only the users
own php process can read their config files with the password in it! And
it also means that files you upload (i.e. wordpress media files) will be
owned by the user, not by www-data or what ever the web user is. This is
SO much better than Apache and mod_php, and easier than suExec with
mod_php.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I have more of my domains moved to Nginx, I'll do a report on
memory and cpu usage.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Nginx"></category><category term="php-fpm"></category><category term="secure"></category><category term="supercache"></category><category term="try_files"></category><category term="wordpress"></category></entry><entry><title>Munin cgi graph timing out</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/09/munin-cgi-graph-timing-out/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-09-01T11:50:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-09-01:2011/09/munin-cgi-graph-timing-out/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A problem that has given lots of people problems, caused me issues
yesterday. I have munin using munin-cgi-graph to create the graphs on
demand due to me not often viewing the graphs. A few days ago I had a
server issue that caused apache to lock up (I think a process ran away
with my RAM which caused swapping and apache to lock up.) Once I apache
running again, I wanted to check the munin graphs to see what the system
looked like during the lockup (which killed a number of processes due to
out of memory conditions). However, the graphs wouldn't generate and the
cgi was timing out without sending any data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;Timeout waiting for output from CGI script /usr/lib/cgi-bin/munin-cgi-graph Premature end of script headers: munin-cgi-graph&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm not alone ether.
&lt;a href="http://wiki.kartbuilding.net/index.php/Further_issues_upgrading_to_Lenny#munin_with_cgi"&gt;http://wiki.kartbuilding.net/index.php/Further_issues_upgrading_to_Lenny#munin_with_cgi&lt;/a&gt;
and &lt;a href="http://forum.linode.com/viewtopic.php?t=5171%3E"&gt;http://forum.linode.com/viewtopic.php?t=5171%3E&lt;/a&gt; both had issues.
More googling still didn't find an answer so I tried to debug the perl
cgi. After using CPAN to get Devel:Trace installed, I discovered the cgi
was sitting waiting for a semaphore flag that it uses to ensure no more
than a certain number of munin-graphs are running at once. This is
great, except when a crash has caused this semaphore to be stuck at the
maximum so no more munin-graph processes get started ever!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are 2 solutions. The first is simple, reboot. The second is also
simple, clear the semaphore flags manually. &lt;code&gt;ipcs&lt;/code&gt; is the command to
show the flags and &lt;code&gt;ipcrm&lt;/code&gt; is the command for removing the semaphores.
Check the man pages for information on the correct syntax.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="ipcrm"></category><category term="ipcs"></category><category term="munin"></category><category term="munin-cgi-graph"></category><category term="semaphore"></category><category term="timeout"></category></entry><entry><title>Day 13</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/08/day-13/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-08-29T13:03:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-08-29:2011/08/day-13/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I think today is Day 13.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So finally I've had a chance to sit down and nut this out. First things
first, getting hello world to run on the iPhone. Finally I worked out
how to self sign a certificate, and get Xcode to build it, then using a
custom script I found on the net, sign the code so the iPhone will run
it. Yay! Hello World runs on the iPhone!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next step. Get a GPS app running on the iPhone. After following a pretty
good tutorial from
http://www.vellios.com/2010/08/16/core-location-gps-tutorial/ I finally
got a GPS test app running. (After making some changes so it would run
on iOS 3.1). However, this is the end of the good news. So far, as I
suspected, the iPhone 3GS isn't performing well on the GPS. Accuracy of
1km isn't good enough, that can be achieved with just network location!
We need down to about 10m. I'm thinking maybe I will need to upgrade to
a newer iOS to see if it's an issue with the hardware or the software.
However I want this app to run on iOS 3.1, so am hesitant to do any
upgrades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last of the good news is that the Objective-C is starting to make
some sense to me, and I'll now work on learning the major differences,
and some more subtle ones, between Objective-C, C++ and
C.&lt;small&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="GPS"></category><category term="iOS"></category><category term="iPhone"></category><category term="XCode"></category></entry><entry><title>Day 6</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/08/day-6/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-08-22T16:53:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-08-22:2011/08/day-6/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So not much has happened over the weekend due to it being very busy.
Today the mini-DVI to HDMI adapter arrived, so I could finally "dock"
the Macbook at my desk. After "docking" it with my monitor, keyboard and
mouse, it suddenly feels less like a laptop and more like a desktop!
More screen realestate is a big bonus. But being able to just pick it
up, pull out a few cables and take it with me, tether it to my mobile
via wifi and work on the go, just makes such a difference to having a
separate desktop and laptop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I already used a password manager under Linux, I wanted an
application that was compatible with my existing password database.
Thankfully, Password Gorilla runs on OS X, and all the other platforms,
and reads the same password database as pwsafe does. So while I was out
today, I finally migrated a number of machine passwords into a secure
"safe". The GUI is rather nice on the Mac, so I may considering using it
under Linux too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also installed Qumana which will allow me to blog without using a
browser. This is something I did many moons ago, and so thought I'd try
it again for this Project as it assists in making me use the Mac for the
whole time, rather than using interfaces/apps/things that I am already
comfortable with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I have a few uni assignments due this week, I probably won't spend
much time working on the project. And unfortunately, at least for one of
the assignments, I will have to use my Linux machine to complete it due
to some tools that aren't available for Mac. I have contemplated
installing Linux on the Mac, but for now figure that the time spent
doing that is better spent on the assignments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, while setting in a shopping centre working today, some
random walked past and said something like "Mac's are nice aren't they?"
So for all those who want people to stop and talk to you, get a Mac!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I have gotten this Mac to the point that it's now very usable
for me. I've installed enough apps to get me going, and I'm forcing
myself to learn all the Mac shortcuts. Now I'll use it for all my
Assignments this week as much as possible, and I think by the end of the
week, I'll probably be using my Linux machine via VNC on my Mac!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Powered by&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.qumana.com/"&gt;Qumana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry><entry><title>Day 3</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/08/day-3/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-08-19T12:15:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-08-19:2011/08/day-3/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've decided to blog this journey of learning and challenge. I am
developing a mobile app, initially for iOS and eventually for Android. I
have given myself an initial 60 days to get it done, 60 days from
getting the equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being an iOS app, I required an Apple Mac computer to run the required
development tools. Tuesday afternoon an iPhone 3GS and a MacBook
arrived, curtsey of a friend of Jun's. First thing I needed to do was
download the Lion update, so I could run XCode 4.1. This started Tuesday
evening and was finished by Wednesday morning (Day 1). I then prepared a
USB Drive to boot the installer from, and went and purchased a new
laptop HDD to upgrade the MacBook. By lunch time I'd fitted the new
500Gb HDD and the OS X Lion install was finished. Now started the 6-8hr
download of XCode. Meanwhile I spent some time getting aquainted with
this MacBook and OS X. No, I'm not converted like some people have been
asking, however it probably will be my main computer for the next 60 odd
days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday (day 2) I wrote a Hello World app in XCode for iOS. It was
copied straight from a tutorial on the net, and I quickly discovered
that Apple wants \$99 from me to be able to even test it on my iPhone!
Come on Apple, you already get the money for the MacBook, the iPhone,
and now you want more money just so we can test apps on our OWN
devices!?!? Eventually we'll need to fork out this money so we can sign
our apps and put them on the App Store. For now though, I think I'll
just jailbreak for testing purposes.&lt;br /&gt;
I've continued getting acquainted with the MacBook. It now runs Firefox
and Thunderbird, iCal is 2 way syncing my calendar. Clementine has
become my music player (iTunes, no thanks), LibreOffice is installed.
TextWrangler may become my other code editor if it is good enough.
Dropbox is setup for syncing between my MacBook and certain folders on
my main computer. So far, it's been nice using this computer, however
it's certainly not better than similar hardware running Linux. For a
start, it took me a long time to get network shares with our NAS working
well, even though it supports AFP. Eventually it was easier to just
setup NFS. I'm getting used to all the keyboard shortcuts, which once
learned certainly speed up some navigation. Annoyingly, there have been
some things where a keyboard doesn't work and you have to use a mouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding code, it looks like I'll probably use Git for the SCM as its
built in to XCode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thats all for Day 3 so far. I need to get some uni work done and we have
a busy weekend. I look forward to next week when I'll have to make this
iPhone run my apps!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Apple"></category><category term="Development"></category><category term="iOS"></category><category term="iPhone"></category><category term="Mac"></category><category term="MacBook"></category><category term="OS X"></category><category term="project"></category><category term="XCode"></category></entry><entry><title>Gmail account hacked :(</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/08/gmail-account-hacked/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-08-04T11:28:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-08-04:2011/08/gmail-account-hacked/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For someone that prides himself on security, it is rather embarrassing
to get hacked. I currently don't know how they got in, or exactly what
they have done. I have changed my passwords and security questions
though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, I know that my account was accessed from Poland (194.181.62.13)
with last access at 8:49 am today. It only appears to have been accessed
via a browser, and there don't seem to be any extra filters (forwarding)
setup. I do know that it appears everyone in my address book has been
sent a link, although the link I can see that was sent (thanks to a
bounce back) doesn't appear to work. They also deleted everything from
my sent box and trash, which is probably what annoys me the most. I
don't know if anything else has been deleted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most likely method they got in by was from an attack on another
site, that revealed my password from when I used the same password in
more than one place. As I no longer do this, I've been slowly changing
my passwords to all be unique, however I should have changed my gmail
one along time ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So 2 morals to this story. Even security conscience people can get
hacked. And backup your data from the cloud if you wish to avoid loosing
anything. I'm now in the process of setting up version controlled
backups of my gmail data.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="gmail"></category><category term="hacked"></category></entry><entry><title>Google+ (Google's Social Network)</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/07/google-googles-social-network/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-07-15T10:57:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-07-15:2011/07/google-googles-social-network/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;By now you should have heard about Google+. You may have some idea of
what it is, or you may have none, so hopefully I can answer some of your
questions and help you get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, Google+ is Google's latest entry into social networking.
Already it looks much better than Buzz or Wave. What I like about it
already is that the interface is clean and simple, and most importantly
it is very easy to control your privacy settings. Now Facebook does have
a similar feature, but it is extremely difficult to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circles. You simple assign your "friends" to different circles, they can
be in more than one. Then, you can share a post/photo/video etc with
different circles, individual people, or the public. (There is also an
extended circles which I believe shares it with people in your circles,
and people in their circles). Want to let the world know about your new
baby, simply post it public! (Like twitter). Want to post how you are
having a dodgy day but only want your friends to know, and not your
boss, just post it to your friends circle and make sure you boss is in
your work circle. Want to share some good news with family and few close
friends, post it to your family circle and then add the extra friends in
as well!&lt;br /&gt;
Circles make it very simple to control who see's what on your Google+
profile. Given the security scares of facebook stalkers and the like,
it's good to know you have total control over who see's what.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently there are no Google+ games or apps. However for me that's a
bonus. I'm sick of all these status updates of "I just completed level
235 of bubble popping game...." and lots of other meaningless things
like that. I don't mind people playing games, but I don't want to hear
about it! What Google+ offers you out of the box though, is an amazing
tool for social network communications that will allow you to easily
keep in contact with people from all areas of your life, without getting
cluttered down in the mechanisms of the communications. Huddles allow
you to create a group of people for discussing something, like a group
assignment, complete with group video chat (which arrived before
Facebook announce the Skype Video partnership).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm hoping that you have read this far and are at least interested in
trying Google+. For many people, until all your friends are there, you
aren't going to move. In fact, unless you are sick of the bloat of
facebook, you probably have very little incentive to move unless you
have privacy concerns with facebook. However I urge to to consider this,
someone has to take the first steps so that others will follow. And if
you need a good reason to take those first steps, I believe the privacy
issues of facebook should be enough for anyone to think twice about
facebook. And, if Google+ does flop, or you want to run away from it,
all the stuff you put on it is yours, there is a nice easy way to
download all your photos and other things on Google+ so you aren't
locked in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now here is the hard part, Google+ is still currently invite only as
it's still in it's "trial" stages while they work out bugs. So below is
a form that you can put your name and email address in, and a short note
if you desire, and I'll invite you to Google+. Due to the demand for
invites, there are 2 things we do to try and get you in. First we send
you an invite, then we share a post with you. You'll get 2 emails, try
the invite one first, which should have a red button to "Learn more
about Google+" which will hopefully take you to the signin page to
create your profile. If that fails, the second email will have a link to
"View or Comment on Blah Blahs Post". This link will also hopefully take
you to a page where you can fill out your public profile and then sign
in to Google+.&lt;br /&gt;
Both methods work at different times, so if it doesn't work for you
immediately, please wait an hour and try again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I promise to not do anything with your email address other than invite
you to Google+. Please be patient as I need to manually invite each
person unless I can work out some way to automate this. I am happy to
invite people I don't know, however please don't be offended if you
don't end up in my circles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Form removed as invites no longer needed)&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="facebook"></category><category term="google+"></category><category term="googleplus"></category><category term="invites"></category><category term="social network"></category></entry><entry><title>Mt Gox Passwords Leaked</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/06/mt-gox-passwords-leaked/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-20T14:37:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-06-20:2011/06/mt-gox-passwords-leaked/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;For the second time in a week, I've heard of a websites user database
being leaked. In the first case it was from a site I've never used. The
second though was a site I signed up to a few months back.&lt;br /&gt;
One of the biggest problems with this leaked database is that the
hashing function used isn't that strong when the hacker has rainbow
tables to use to crack the database.&lt;br /&gt;
The first side effect of this for me was to go and change some of my
passwords as a precautionary measure. The second side effect, and the
more annoying one, is that I used a private email address for this
particular account instead of using one of my "junk" gmail addresses. So
now my private email address is in the hands of every hacker who is
trying to crack that database. And already we are receiving "spam" to
those addresses in that database. Most of it so far is users ether
letting you know the Mt Gox database has been hacked, or users/owners of
other Bitcoin exchanges sending you "advertising" so you'll come start
using their exchange. I've email gotten an email advertising online
storage from a company that accepts Bitcoins as payments. And they
haven't bothered to try and keep the email addresses slightly private,
1500 other people also have my address, and I have theirs, as no Bcc was
used. (Of course, spam filtering will quickly filter that particular
email out).&lt;br /&gt;
Interested to see how bad the compromise was, and if it'll affect me,
I've also downloaded the user database now. A quick look shows that my
password is hashed with the less secure method and a quick bit of code
later I can confirm the password I used to make that hash. Luckily for
me, I use pwdhash to generate a unique password for each site I use.
This means that an attacker who has cracked my hashed password in the Mt
Gox password, still only has a password that can be used for one site,
Mt Gox. If they had enough time and power, then maybe they could work
backwards and eventually find the password I used to generate my pwdhash
passwords, but by the time they did this, I'd have changed all those
passwords anyway.&lt;br /&gt;
Having only been using pwdhashing for a little while now, it was good
to discover that it has already protected me from an attack. A number of
user who had simple passwords that have been cracked already, have also
had other accounts attacked as they used the same password in multiple
places.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An interesting side note is how much the Mt Gox Bitcoin exchange has
grown in a very short space of time. A discussion taking place in a
forum noted that your position in the database is related to when you
signed up. Working from knowing when you signed up shows how many people
signed up after you. It seems to have had exponential growth in the last
few weeks, which is good for Bitcoin in general, but bad once you
realise how this will look to all those new users. Looking at my
position in the database, I can see I was a very early adopter.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bitcoin"></category><category term="crack"></category><category term="database"></category><category term="leaked"></category><category term="mt gox"></category><category term="password"></category></entry><entry><title>Drupal Upgrades</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/06/drupal-upgrades/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-10T16:42:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-06-10:2011/06/drupal-upgrades/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Drupal upgrades have not been easy, and they should be easy. You look at
wordpress, one click and the upgrade is done! Plugins, themes and core
can all be upgraded from in the browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drupal upgrades are traditionally backup, move all files out, extract
new fresh files, move selected files back. Now there is an easier way!
Patch files from &lt;a href="http://fuerstnet.de/en/drupal-upgrade-easier"&gt;http://fuerstnet.de/en/drupal-upgrade-easier&lt;/a&gt; allow
you to backup, and then inplace upgrade the Drupal core files! No nasty
moving things around that is almost guaranteed to break something
because you forgot to move something back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still look forward to the day when Drupal upgrades are as easy as
Wordpress. Until then, I have a good enough method!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="drupal"></category><category term="upgrades"></category></entry><entry><title>Disable IPv6 in Transmission BT</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/06/disable-ipv6-in-transmission-bt/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-10T15:59:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-06-10:2011/06/disable-ipv6-in-transmission-bt/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;After finally getting my IPv6 working nicely, it was time to prevent
Transmission from using IPv6 as  I don't want lots of torrent traffic
going through the tunnel when it's faster through IPv4 (until a time I
can get Native IPv6). Apparently this is an "invalid" feature request
according to some of the developers.
(&lt;a href="http://trac.transmissionbt.com/ticket/4197"&gt;http://trac.transmissionbt.com/ticket/4197&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Had the developer actually stopped to consider it, maybe read some
relevant parts of the source code, they would have quickly discovered
that you can already disable it! They could document it as a feature
without having to touch a line of code, and mark the feature request as
completed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's a rather simple fix. There are checks for the IPv6 address not
being a link local address, or a 6to4, or Teredo tunnel[1]. So we just
make Transmission bind to a link local address and hey presto, no IPv6
for Transmission!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply add the following line to the settings.json file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&amp;quot;bind-address-ipv6&amp;quot;: &amp;quot;fe80::&amp;quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;[1] You'd think given that they already prevent Teredo tunnels from
being used, that the feature request would actually make sense for those
wishing to disable IPv6 due to TUNNEL's!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="ipv6"></category><category term="torrent"></category><category term="transmission"></category><category term="tunnel"></category></entry><entry><title>Why we need native IPv6</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/06/why-we-need-native-ipv6/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-10T12:12:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-06-10:2011/06/why-we-need-native-ipv6/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;We need native IPv6, or at least a decent PoP in Australia!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently our home network is IPv6 enabled via a Sixxs tunnel. If we
lived in NZ then our PoP would be in NZ. Unfortunately we can't use the
NZ PoP, so instead we use the London PoP! Eventually I'll get around to
pinging every PoP available to us and find the "closest" one, but for
now, letter the numbers do the talking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I ping the same machine both via IPv6 and via IPv4. Lets see if you can
work out which is which.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;10 packets transmitted, 10 received, 0% packet loss
rtt min/avg/max/mdev = 698.592/712.159/814.473/34.163 ms

10 packets transmitted, 10 received, 0% packet loss
rtt min/avg/max/mdev = 76.670/79.557/87.452/2.866 ms
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The PoP has an average ping of 350ms just to get to the PoP! No wonder
it takes so long to get to the PoP and back to Australia! Hopefully
later in the year my hosting provider will have fixed the IPv6 transport
and I can setup my own local tunnel. Until then, slow IPv6 :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;ins datetime="2011-06-10T02:48:46+00:00"&gt;Edit: So I finally got AARNet
IPv6 tunnel broker service working. A much better improvement. I'm
running both tunnels in parrallel so that if one dies the other is
working. Hopefully I'll see better IPv6 improvement now. Still, native
IPv6 would be better.
&lt;a href="http://michael-wheeler.org/2009/03/24/australian-ipv6-tunnel-broker/"&gt;http://michael-wheeler.org/2009/03/24/australian-ipv6-tunnel-broker/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;10 packets transmitted, 10 received, 0% packet loss
rtt min/avg/max/mdev = 235.587/267.187/382.010/45.090 ms
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="ipv6"></category><category term="ping"></category><category term="sixxs"></category></entry><entry><title>"The Ultimate Steal" is right</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/06/the-ultimate-steal-is-right/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-02T14:17:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-06-02:2011/06/the-ultimate-steal-is-right/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Microsoft's student "Its not stealing" campaign is supposed to make it
easy for students to afford Microsoft products so they don't need to
pirate them (and steal them). That's fine as long as it works and
Microsoft don't steal from us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twice I've now attempted to place an order with the online system, twice
the order has been denied however the pre-authorisation on my credit
card means I'm now \$300 "out of pocket" until the transactions are
reversed in the next 5 business days. I've called my bank (before trying
to place the order the second time) to ensure that there wasn't a
problem with my account or the credit card. No problem from the banks
end, it should have gone through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fittingly the email I got from them after complaining comes from "The
Ultimate Steal AU". We'll it sure is the ultimate steal, lets take your
money and give you nothing. And yes, I know I get the money back, but
it's my time and effort I'm wasting, and if I needed that money to pay a
bill, it's not there. Experiences like this sure make me want to buy
from Micro\$oft!! Oh, and if I was rich and had lots of money in my
account, each time I hit submit to attempt again (like the text
suggests) would be another \$150 pre-authorisation without success. Not
a great payment system if you ask me, no safety limits to prevent you
from trying again and again. You could easily have a few thousand
dollars in pre-auth as you keep checking the details, sure they are
correct, you hit submit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully they can fix it faster than the amount of time I spent on hold
just to be told they can't do anything!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="digital river"></category><category term="micro$oft"></category><category term="microsoft"></category><category term="steal"></category></entry><entry><title>Remote Scan to PDF</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/04/remote-scan-to-pdf/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-04-20T16:42:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-04-20:2011/04/remote-scan-to-pdf/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I needed a simple and quick way for other users on the network to be
able to scan documents. So far, what I had been doing was running a
little bash script I found on the net, and scanning multiple pages into
a pdf. The problem was that I needed to run it, and teaching everyone
else to login via ssh and run it wasn't an option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I knocked together a little PHP application that did the basic things
the bash script does. It can even customise the settings (however that
is disabled atm due to a scanner problem). And to make it more natural,
I used jQuery and AJAX to run the jobs in the background without having
a script constantly reloading itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Warning, the script in it's current version has basically no security.
As there is a "readfile" part to dump the PDF to the browser, a user
could easily make it read any file the web server has access too. It
also has minimal error checking as generally things just work, and if
they don't, you start again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you are looking for a simple solution for network access to your
scanner, and you don't want to go as far as phpsane, then here is the
code! &lt;a href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/code/phpscan2pdf/files"&gt;http://tim.purewhite.id.au/code/phpscan2pdf/files&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="code"></category><category term="pdf"></category><category term="php"></category><category term="scan2pdf"></category><category term="scanner"></category><category term="scanning"></category></entry><entry><title>Disk recovery - Which files are damaged?</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/04/disk-recovery-which-files-are-damaged/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-04-19T09:40:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-04-19:2011/04/disk-recovery-which-files-are-damaged/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;ins datetime="2011-08-11T21:49:04+00:00"&gt;First, getting an image of the
damaged hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;ddrescue -n /dev/inputdevice rescued.img rescued.log

&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;ddrescue -r &lt;span class="m"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt; /dev/inputdevice rescued.img rescued.log
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The first ddrescue command tries to fly through the disk as quickly as
possible, skipping over sections when an error occurs. This allows me to
recover most of the good data as quickly as possible. The second command
(which is only needed if you had errors found with the first command)
will then retry the bad sections of disk, splitting the error sections
into smaller and smaller parts until you eventually have individual
blocks that are damaged. It is here that ddrescue really works hard to
recover your data, and this part can take just as long as the first
part.&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you have successfully used ddrescue to recover everything you can off
a failing hard drive. Now you have a big image file, maybe 500Gb, with
sectors that could be recovered, and those that couldn't. But how do you
find which files belong to the broken sectors? I recently had this
problem with a FAT32 filesystem. After lots and lots of googling, I
still didn't have a decent answer. Windows has a tool called DiskView,
however it doesn't appear to work on disk images. There is also a Hex
viewer around that apparently will tell you which files belong to the
sector you are viewing, but I had no luck with that ether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually I stumbled across a toolset I should have used from the
start. The Sleuth Kit. I also stumbled across a paper someone had
written doing some forensics with The Sleuth Kit which pointed me to the
right tools, although some had changed names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, let me first point you to a fairly simple way that is hidden in
the ddrescue info pages. While at first it sounds like this method
should be the long hard way, it actually works out to be the easiest
way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is suggested in the ddrescue info pages that you md5sum all the files
in the image, then using ddrescue in fill mode you write some data (that
isn't all zero's) to the sections that couldn't be recovered, and then
md5sum all the files again and compare. Seeing as I had already copied
all the files off the image, it was actually even simplier than that. I
wrote the random data to the damaged sections (in this case "BADSECTOR"
over and over again) and then did a diff between the files on the image
and the files I had already copied off the image. It did take awhile to
do the diff, but 4hrs to compare 180Gb of files with 180Gb of files,
over a network isn't that bad. I'm sure it would have been a lot quicker
had all the files resided on the local machine on  a nice RAID array.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So a simplified example&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;copy all files off rescued image (loop mount) to another location&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; -n &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;BAD SECTOR &amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;gt; tmpfile
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;ddrescue --fill&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;- tmpfile rescue.img rescue.log

&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;diff -r /mnt/loop/ /mnt/server/rescuedfiles/ &amp;gt; damagedfiles
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;You'll then have a list of files that differ between the 2 versions,
which are the ones with damaged sectors. Also, the ddrescue doesn't
damage the logfile so you can then reverse it using /dev/zero to restore
the image to it's original recovery state. This won't work with sparse
files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;ddrescue --fill&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;- /dev/zero rescue.img rescue.log
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;ins datetime="2011-08-11T21:54:00+00:00"&gt;Or, if you haven't copied the
files off, then the way suggested in the ddrescue manual looks like
this. (After getting your disk image)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;# mount -o loop rescued.img /mnt/loop

$ find /mnt/loop -type f -print0 | xargs -0 md5sum &amp;gt; prefill.md5

$ echo -n &amp;quot;BAD SECTOR &amp;quot; &amp;gt; tmpfile
$ ddrescue --fill=- tmpfile rescue.img rescue.log

## You may need to unmount and remount the loop file to prevent any caching interferring.
# umount /mnt/loop
# mount -o loop rescued.img /mnt/loop

$ find /mnt/loop -type f -print0 | xargs -0 md5sum &amp;gt; postfill.md5

$ diff prefill.md5 postfill.md5
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;ins datetime="2011-08-11T21:42:04+00:00"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is all you need when
trying to work out which files are damaged. The following is another
method for really peaking into the file system that may be more useful
for deeper analysis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if you do want to find out which files are in the damaged
sectors, then continue as it is possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, check that the sector is actually used. This used to be the dstat
command, but it has since been renamed to blkstat. So we take a sector
number from the logfile that couldn't be recovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;cat rescue.log &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;grep -&lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;head
0x0178F200  0x0000D400  -
0x017A0000  0x00000200  -
0x2BC488F400  0x00011600  -
0x2BEEFF0A00  0x00020000  -
0x5AC5FB0A00  0x00020000  -
0x5AC6050A00  0x00020000  -
0x5AC60E0A00  0x00020000  -
0x5AC6180A00  0x00020000  -
0x5AC6220A00  0x00020000  -
0x5AC62B0A00  0x00020000  -
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We then convert it to a sector number. I know the sector size is 512
bytes in this case, but you will need to verify it for your drive. If in
doubt, do the conversion, open a hexeditor, jump to that location, use
the previous ddrescue command to fill in the badsectors with some known
next, and confirm that the known text is at the address you are
viewing.&lt;br /&gt;
I've picked sector 0x2BEEFF0A00 to analyise. So I convert it to decimal
and dived by 512 (the sector size). I can do this all at once if I know
that 512 in hex is 200.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;ibase=16; 2BEEFF0A00/200&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;bc
368541573
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Or do it the long way&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;ibase=16; 2BEEFF0A00&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;bc
188693285376
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;echo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s2"&gt;&amp;quot;188693285376/512&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;bc
368541573
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Ether way, I now know that the sector number is 368541573. Using blkstat
(formerly dstat) I can verify that the sector is used or not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;blkstat rescued.img 368541573
Sector: 368541573
Allocated
Cluster: 5754738
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now a little warning, if you get a sector that looks like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;blkstat rescued.img 48249
Sector: 48249
Allocated &lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Meta&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Then you are probably looking at a sector in a directory listing. The
next tool we are going to use, ifind, may take a very long time to
process that sector for almost no gain. I would leave these sectors
until you have processed the others. I believe this one for me actually
is in one of the FAT's, which just told me that the FAT was probably
damaged. What I can do is work with the damaged FAT initially, then
switch over to the other FAT and see what is different. (Which I won't
cover in this post) &lt;ins datetime="2011-04-18T23:52:56+00:00"&gt;On further
investigation, it turns out this sector was in an unused part of the
FAT, so had caused no damage to the FAT. Damage to the fat could prevent
you from even seeing some of the files, so hopefully when you have
damage to the FAT your 2nd FAT will still be good.&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our next step is to use ifind to find the inode associated with the
sector. This can take some time and lots of CPU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="nb"&gt;time &lt;/span&gt;ifind rescued.img -d 368541573
5892375559

real    2m52.314s
user    1m15.280s
sys 0m2.170s
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This finally gives us the inode associated with that file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;istat rescued.img 5892375559&lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;head -12
Directory Entry: 5892375559
Allocated
File Attributes: File, Archive
Size: 21346140
Name: MICROS~1

Directory Entry Times:
Written:    Wed Aug &lt;span class="m"&gt;25&lt;/span&gt; 22:16:38 2010
Accessed:   Wed Apr &lt;span class="m"&gt;13&lt;/span&gt; 00:00:00 2011
Created:    Wed Aug &lt;span class="m"&gt;25&lt;/span&gt; 22:16:39 2010

Sectors:
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;The listing then goes on to show all sectors that the file uses. If we
grep the listing, we can confirm that the sector 5892375559 is in that
file. Unfortunately, we are stuck with the 8.3 filename and not the
complete filename. Thankfully another tool will come to our rescue. If
you are looking for a good number of files that are affected (i.e. more
than 1 or 2 sectors) you'll want to run this command without the grep,
and save the contents to a file so you can just grep over that file each
time as it takes a long time to recursively list all the files in a big
filesystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;fls -rFp bunsom.img &lt;span class="p"&gt;|&lt;/span&gt;grep 5892375559
r/r 5892375559: Microsoft Office 2011/Office/Microsoft Chart Converter.app/Contents/MacOS/Microsoft Chart Converter
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;So finally we can see that the inode 5892375559, which contains our
damaged sector, belongs to this file from the Microsoft Office Chart
Converter App. (Yes, it does look a little strange this file but that's
because it's a OS X App file).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can now repeat this for all damaged sectors. However, I'd be first
getting a list of all sectors (remember that the second column in the
ddrescue log is size of the damaged area, use that to work out who many
sectors in a row are damaged). I'd then check the file we have just
found (use the istat tool) to see if any of the other damaged sectors
are also in that file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;keywords to assist others finding it: data recovery, damaged sector,
file at sector, file belong to sector, sector contents, damaged files,
fat32, sector explore, sector view&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Comments&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leave a comment by adding to the &lt;a href="https://github.com/timwhite/technicallytim/issues/1"&gt;issue on
Github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Comment from &lt;a href="https://github.com/amichair"&gt;amichair&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks for the article, it's been very helpful!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A few updates that might save time for the next person to need it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;instead of the hex calculations and using bc, one can simply use 'ddrescuelog
-l- ddrescue.log'. This outputs all the bad ('-') sector numbers in decimal,
i.e. it does both the division by sector size and conversion to decimal, and in
addition it outputs all the sectors and not just the first one of each series
of bad blocks (you mention this in the last paragraph but with no example of
how to do this). So this one command takes care of a lot of stuff in one fell
swoop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;in some larger disks nowadays the sector size is 4096 rather than 512. Thus
calculating the 'data unit' used in the sleuthkit tools might require an
additional division by 8 (after division by 512).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the version of sleuthkit in Ubuntu (up to 13.10, and it looks like it won't
change by the 14.04 release this week) is a couple years old, and as it turns
out, does not support ext4. While this is platform-specific (though pretty
common platform), the important note is that blkstat works ok, but then ifind
says 'inode not found', which is a bit perplexing considering it is marked as
'Allocated'. So the filesystem auto-detection fails silently. Only if one
specifies '-f ext4' explicitly does he find out that ext4 is not supported. I
had to download and build the latest sleuthkit myself for it to work with ext4
properly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks once again for this great tutorial!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</summary><category term="damaged"></category><category term="fat32"></category><category term="recovery"></category><category term="sector"></category></entry><entry><title>Are mobile Providers Ripping Us Off?</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/04/are-mobile-providers-ripping-us-off/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-04-08T18:17:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-04-08:2011/04/are-mobile-providers-ripping-us-off/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;With so many options, so many plans, it's hard to know if we are being
ripped off or getting a good deal. Then bring in VoIP, and things get
even trickier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the sake of this research, I was looking for a mobile phone plan,
prepaid or post paid, that would ideally cost less than $40 a month and
didn't rely on any VoIP. (Due to data connections being unreliable and
sometimes VoIP applications are difficult, like calling an access number
then dialing the rest of your number). I firstly crunched just the
numbers, to get an idea of what Mobile Cap plans actually give you in
real dollars, not cap dollars, and how that would translate into minutes
of talk time or sms's. Finally, I took my actual usage logs (which my
Android saves to my Gmail account for me via SMS Backup+), and crunched
the numbers to work out how much that usage would cost me on each plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, a bit about  my method in crunching the numbers. Most mobile
providers charge in 1 or 3 ways, per second, per 30 seconds, or per
minute. If you make long calls, then per minute billing won't really
make much of a difference, but if you make short calls, then per minute
billing could end up costing you lots. For example, if all my calls are
less than 30 seconds long, and I'm on per minute billing, then I'm
always paying for a minute, even though I've used less than half of
that!&lt;br /&gt;
Using that, I figured that splitting my calls in to 3 categories would
allow me to best see the cost difference between per second, per 30
second, and per minute billing. Calls less than 30 seconds, Calls more
than 30 seconds but less than a minute, and calls longer than a minute.
I then wrote my formulas using the split categories, using the average
call length for each category and the number of calls. To verify that
this wasn't skewing my data, I then took 1 month and calculated the
total cost processing each call to the second, for per second, per 30
second and per minute billing. The results were almost 100% the same
between the 2 methods. You are welcome to show me some mathematical
proof as to why this happens, just know that if I take the average
length of all calls for the month, and don't split them into categories,
then the results are not close and the providers offering per second
billing loose their advantage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, as you may have already worked out, per second billing can really
save you money. Which is probably why more and more providers are moving
away from per second billing towards per minute billing. You'll notice a
lot of VoIP providers advertise per second billing, which is because
people know that they are only paying for what they use. For example, my
scenario outcome for one month on one particular per minute biller,
comes out to $311, but if they offered per 30 second billing like they
previously did, I'd save $32 worth of cap credit, or about $2 of real
money. Not much, but as you can see, it's extra money in the providers
pockets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I started my research, I expected to find that these Cap plans are
ripping us off with the illusion of lots of money (cap credit) for very
little real money. I also expected to find that per second billing would
save us the most money. And I hoped to find a provider that would be
better value than my current one. Well, a lot of my expectations have
been crushed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead, what I've found is that while the Cap plans do have a very high
call rate, and high flag fall, they are actually good value.&lt;strong&gt;Note
however, that the numbers I'm about to quote assume that you ether use
&lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; the cap credit on a call, or on sms's, and don't take into account
flagfalls (which would be charged for each call).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A plan with a $0.99 per minute call rate, costs $0.06 per minute in
real dollars.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;The same plan with $0.28 sms rate, costs $0.02 per sms in real
dollars.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I first saw these numbers, I was shocked. So for comparison, I
looked at one of the cheapest VoIP providers. $0.105 per minute, no
flagfall and per second billing. And $0.05 per sms. Yes, you read that
correctly, the mobile phone is cheaper! Now before you trash your VoIP,
that VoIP rate is to mobile phones in Australia, calls to Landlines and
of course, overseas calls will be cheaper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the plans I was looking at thinking should work out cheaper, is
actually a VoIP providers plan. They provider a mobile sim card, with
decent call rates, and free calls to their VoIP numbers, so you can then
make your normal call. But as you can see above, even with the VoIP call
being made over the mobile network, it is still cheaper with this Cap
plan! I had also been thinking of using a callback VoIP provider, I call
an access number, it hangs up and calls me back, then I dial the number
I want and it calls the other side. No cost on the mobile side (except I
need to have credit to make the call, even though I'm not charged for
the call). Yet this requires 2 calls via the VoIP provider, one back to
my mobile, and one to whom ever I'm calling, and at $0.105 a minute,
that's $0.21 a minute all up!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So when is VoIP cheaper then? It's cheaper for international, and
untimed calls, for example, calls to landlines in Australia and a number
of other countries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, at the end of the day, Mobile providers aren't ripping us off, well,
not as much as I thought. Yes, per minute billing means more money to
the providers, and Caps that you don't use completely are also wasting
some money. But even with the months of very light usage, the Cap still
works out cheaper than going with other plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My recommendation, go for a Cap plan that gives you enough Cap $'s that
you won't go over (especially if going post-paid) but you also won't
have heaps unused each month. Then, if your phone can, setup VoIP and
use it for calls to fixed lines. (This could be via mobile data or WiFi
depending on how good the 3G is where you live).  If you don't call
mobiles much, or SMS, and get good 3G in your area, then a Data only
plan with VoIP might be a better choice, as long as you are sure you
don't need normal mobile voice service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/images/2011/04/Phone-Comparison.png"&gt;&lt;img alt="Phone Comparison" src="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/images/2011/04/Phone-Comparison-300x126.png" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NB: Yes, I have taken into account Free calls between phones on the same
carriers, however I only used calls between me and my wife as fitting
into this category, as they are the only calls we can guarantee to be on
the same network.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Cap Plan"></category><category term="Comparison"></category><category term="Exetel"></category><category term="iinet"></category><category term="Mobile"></category><category term="Optus"></category><category term="Pennytel"></category><category term="Phone"></category><category term="Post Paid"></category><category term="Pre Paid"></category><category term="Provider"></category><category term="Telstra"></category><category term="Virgin"></category><category term="voip"></category></entry><entry><title>What it takes to keep things running. (How to reduce comment/wiki spam)</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/04/what-it-takes-to-keep-things-running-how-to-reduce-commentwiki-spam/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-04-05T22:13:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-04-05:2011/04/what-it-takes-to-keep-things-running-how-to-reduce-commentwiki-spam/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently pushed out a new version of the &lt;a href="http://hotspot.purewhite.id.au/"&gt;GRASE Hotspot&lt;/a&gt;. I spent
lots of time working on rewriting the splash/welcome page, and login
forms so that they would work even with javascript disabled, and allow
you to force it into the non javascript version if you are having
problems (so browsers like Safari can be used). However, recently I've
spent a lot of time just doing maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maintenance started when again I spent lots of time cleaning up spam
on the wiki, this was after enabling ReCAPTCHA. I decided it wasn't
practical to keep cleaning up the wiki, and seeing as I was the only one
contributing to it, it made more sense migrating it to a Wordpress site.
After the migration was done, I quickly started getting comment spam on
the new site!! Thankfully, Akismet blocks comment spam, but the volume
of spam coming in was enormous! A peek into the server logs showed that
the same ip's that were publishing spam in the wiki, would try to get
post to the missing wiki, find it missing and discover the wordpress
site and immediately try to post comment spam! It was time to reduce the
load on the server if possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some research, I implemented some basic .htaccess rules that would
block some of the spam even getting processed. But why couldn't I find a
simple DNSBL for Apache? Turns out the right googling will find
libapache2-mod-spamhaus, which does what we need. But unlike email spam,
it seems comment/wiki spammers aren't in the DNSBL's as much as email
spammers. Thankfully, libapache2-mod-spamhaus was now dropping about
half the spamming connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some more research turned up &lt;a href="http://www.projecthoneypot.org?rf=93412" title="Project Honey Pot"&gt;Project Honey Pot&lt;/a&gt; which is aimed more
at the comment spammers and address harvesters. A quick check of the ip
database they maintain revealed that most of the remaining comment
spammer ips that were hitting my site were in their database!
Unfortunately, the mod_httpbl module for Apache isn't in a nice
repository anywhere, and hasn't been touched for awhile, so setup wasn't
as easy. I found &lt;a href="http://repel.in-progress.com/"&gt;Repel&lt;/a&gt; which is a simple Python program that you use
with mod_rewrite (and RewriteMap's). It's not so easy to setup, mainly
due to the instructions being a little unclear, but also because the
rewrite rules that use Repel can be very tricky. The documentation was
good for just blocking, however I figured if I was going to use Project
Honey Pot, I should contribute too, so I setup a honeypot on the site
and then had fun and games with rewrite rules. Eventually though, I got
it all setup. Now if you are thinking of setting this up yourself, it's
probably a lot easier using the &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/httpbl/" title="Wordpress Http:bl Plugin"&gt;Wordpress Plugin&lt;/a&gt; which I've since
setup on another site I assist with. While this will block the spammers,
or direct them to a honeypot, it may have slightly more load than Repel.
This is because Repel is a little python program, that apache already
has running, and just passes the ipaddress to and waits for a reply. The
wordpress plugin solution requires Apache to fire up PHP, which then
fires up Wordpress, which then loads the plugin which finally gets the
ipaddress, does the DNS lookup and then goes from there. I've done no
testing, but logically Repel would appear to use less resources, but you
are welcome to prove me wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of all that maintenance, I also had some mail servers receiving
spam, which should have been blocked. Some more tweaks and changes, and
another influx of spam is now not getting past the gate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, some advice. Password advice. In particular because I heard an
"expert" on the ABC radio recently giving some poor advice. Get yourself
a strong password, with letters and numbers, maybe some capital letters
as well as lowercase, and decent length, at least 8 characters long. Now
use that password for one place, and only one place, maybe your email
account. Now find another one, just as strong, use that for your next
account, maybe facebook. Reusing passwords is a big No No, as an
important CEO recently discovered.&lt;br /&gt;
I can hear you already, moaning and groaning. It's so hard to remember
one really strong password, how can you remember more than one? Well
this is the easy part. You use a formula. I've started using
&lt;a href="https://www.pwdhash.com/" title="PwdHash"&gt;PwdHash&lt;/a&gt;, developed by Standford University. It simply takes the
domain name of the site you are generating the password, and your master
password, and creates you a "hash" that you use as your password for
that site. So for example, if my master password was
'thecatsatonthemat', my facebook password would be
'F58VFRH8eUejfcIs9UA'. This will let you create strong unique passwords
for each account, then if one of your accounts is broken into and the
password somehow discovered, your other accounts are safe. Of course, if
your email account gets broken into, a lot of other accounts are not
safe as the hacker can then just reset your passwords by using the "Lost
Password" feature many sites provide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do decide to use PwdHash, you can install a firefox extension
that assist, or you can use it directly on the site (as it uses
Javascript, your password never leaves the computer, you can even save
the page and use it offline). I found a little python script that does
it for me, which I have on my server and my machine, so I can create my
pwdhash's even when I don't have a browser handy. Of course, there is
nothing preventing you having multiple master passwords ether, just to
make it even more secure!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="password"></category><category term="project honey pot"></category><category term="pwdhash"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="spam"></category></entry><entry><title>Coova Chilli &amp; FreeRadius Reply-Message</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/04/coova-chilli-freeradius-reply-message/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-04-03T01:45:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-04-03:2011/04/coova-chilli-freeradius-reply-message/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I was going to post this on the Grase Hotspot site, but will post it
here in depth and just the basics on the hotspot site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously I researched this problem and found very little, it would
seem since my last search more material has become available that has
assisted. In particular
&lt;a href="http://freeradius.1045715.n5.nabble.com/RESOLVED-customize-Post-Auth-Type-REJECT-td2779460.html"&gt;http://freeradius.1045715.n5.nabble.com/RESOLVED-customize-Post-Auth-Type-REJECT-td2779460.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The basic problem is this. Using CoovaChilli, when a login failed for
some reason, we usually didn't get an error message. If your data quota
had been used up, then maybe you'd get "Your maximum never usage time
has been reached" which for most people was confusing. An expired
account may give you the error "Password Has Expired". However, any
other reason for a login failure and you'd usually not get a message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, you may want to blame Coova Chilli. After all, it is the piece
of software sending back the login failed status, and if using the JSON
interface, it would send back the login failure message. However, good
CoovaChilli is just relaying the message it gets from the Radius server.
So we next turn our attention to FreeRadius.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first place you may be tempted to look is in
/etc/freeradius/modules/expiration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;expiration&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="c1"&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="c1"&gt;# The Reply-Message which will be sent back in case the&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="c1"&gt;# account has expired. Dynamic substitution is supported&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="c1"&gt;#&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="na"&gt;reply-message&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;Password Has Expired\r\n&amp;quot; &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;        #reply-message = &amp;quot;Your account has expired, %{User-Name}\r\n&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="err"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This file gives you false hope. You see the option reply-message and
think, if the expiration has a reply-message, then surely I can just
drop a similar thing in at other places. However, what you don't realise
is that the reply-message is an option for the expiration module.
Internally the module has settings it understands, and other modules
won't understand those same settings! There is no setting for the sql
modules, or the sections that handle counting remaining quota. Putting
this reply-message option in other places will just cause FreeRadius to
fail to start.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By now, if you have read the link above, you may have some better
understanding of what to do. A good place to start reading for better
understanding of how freeradius reads it's config files is &lt;code&gt;man unlang&lt;/code&gt;.
unlang is the "language" used by the config files, and reading it and
some of the accompanying documents with freeradius will enlighten you to
how things work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'll give you a large block of finished code, so you can start to
understand where all this fits together. This is an exceprt of
/etc/freeradius/sites-available/default with comments stripped out.
Please don't just copy and paste this, it's to give better understanding
of where the parts go, as many examples don't give you the context of
the changes needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;authorize&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="err"&gt;preprocess&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="err"&gt;chap&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="err"&gt;mschap&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="err"&gt;suffix&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="err"&gt;eap&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="na"&gt;ok&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;    }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;    sql{&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;        notfound = 1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;        reject = 2&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;    }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;    if(notfound){&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;        update reply {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;            Reply-Message := &amp;quot;Login Failed. Please check your Username and Password&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;        }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;        reject&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;    }&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="err"&gt;if(reject){&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="err"&gt;update&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;reply&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="na"&gt;Reply-Message :&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;Login Failed. Please check your Username and Password&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;        }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;        reject&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;    }&lt;/span&gt;


    &lt;span class="err"&gt;expiration{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="na"&gt;userlock&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;    }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;    if(userlock){&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;            update reply {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;                    Reply-Message := &amp;quot;Your account has expired, %{User-Name}&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;            }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;            reject&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;    }&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="err"&gt;logintime&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="err"&gt;noresetBytecounter{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="na"&gt;reject&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;    }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;    if(reject){&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;            update reply {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;                    Reply-Message := &amp;quot;You have reached your bandwidth limit&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;            }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;            reject&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;    }&lt;/span&gt;


    &lt;span class="err"&gt;noresetcounter{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="na"&gt;reject&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;    }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;    if(reject){&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;            update reply {&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;                    Reply-Message := &amp;quot;You have reached your time limit&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;            }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;            reject&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;    }&lt;/span&gt;

    &lt;span class="err"&gt;pap&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="err"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="err"&gt;post-auth&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="err"&gt;sql&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="err"&gt;exec&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="err"&gt;Post-Auth-Type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;REJECT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="err"&gt;update&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;reply&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="c1"&gt;# Fallback error message&lt;/span&gt;
            &lt;span class="na"&gt;Reply-Message&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;Login Failed. Please check your username and password&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;        }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;        attr_filter.access_reject&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;    }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="err"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I'll start with the part that will help explain the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;noresetBytecounter{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="na"&gt;reject&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="err"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="err"&gt;if(reject){&lt;/span&gt;
        &lt;span class="err"&gt;update&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;reply&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class="na"&gt;Reply-Message :&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;You have reached your bandwidth limit&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;        }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;        reject&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="err"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;When I first saw this code, I thought it was setting a variable reject
to the value of 1. However it's not quite like that. See all modules
have return codes. For example, an ok code, or a reject or fail code.
However, that code is more than just a code, it also has an action with
it. For example, a reject code has the action, reject. Rather simple.
What the reject action does, is stop processing this section and return
a reject. What the 'reject = 1' does, is says that if this module
returns a reject, we set the action to a 1, which is setting it's
priority to 1, so that we can process more modules and get their error
codes too, and give them priorities, so the highest priority code wins.
This would let us do complex things for example, letting us exceed our
bandwidth limit as long as our time limit is also exceeded. Given that
we can have priorities from 1 to 99999 we can actually do really complex
things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what this first bit of code is doing then, is preventing a reject
from being sent straight away, so we can do more processing. And the
next bit of processing we do is test for that reject. (You may think
that this test could catch an earlier reject, but only if an earlier
reject also had it's priority set to something otherwise it's default
action would have been to return a reject straight away.) If this reject
exists, then the module noresetBytecounter must have triggered it. So we
update the reply package that FreeRadius is going to return, and set the
Reply-Message to an appropriate error message given then module that
caused the failure. We then send that reject without processing more
modules with the "reject" line. We could do other things like
sending an 'return' which would clear the reject and return an ok.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the rest of that big piece of code is similar pieces of code,
although some have different codes, like userlock. The other important
piece of code sets a default message for Access-Reject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;post-auth&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="err"&gt;sql&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="err"&gt;exec&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class="err"&gt;Post-Auth-Type&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;REJECT&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
                &lt;span class="err"&gt;update&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;reply&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="c1"&gt;# Fallback error message&lt;/span&gt;
                    &lt;span class="na"&gt;Reply-Message&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;quot;Login Failed. Please check your username and password&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;                }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;        attr_filter.access_reject&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="s"&gt;    }&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="err"&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;It's rather easy to see what is happening here. In the post-auth section
(same file as the rest of the stuff), we match the Reject packets. We
then update the reply, with a generic error message. Because of the
operators (= .vs. :=) it will only add this Reply-Message if there is no
other Reply-Message already set in the Access-Reject. We used := before
to replace any Reply-Message already existing, so for example we could
override the cryptic message sthe the sql_counter module sends back. We
could also use += if we want to "Append" Reply-Messages, allowing
multiple messages to be sent back. The "attr_filter.access_reject"
line is nothing to worry about, it just filters the return Access-Reject
packet to ensure only allowed attributes are sent back. As Reply-Message
is allowed, it isn't stripped out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully that gives better understanding to what code is needed to
change/set the Reply-Message in Access-Reject packets. It could also be
used to send back messages with Access-Accept packets. The great thing
is that there are a good number of return codes, which allow you to make
some really complex changes to how the data flows. If you have read the
link at the start, you should by now start to realise how powerful
unlang is. Not only can you check return codes, you can also check parts
of the packet that have been "constructed". You can also change much
more than the Reply-Message, you can change if it's access is accepted
or rejected, what bandwidth controls are sent back, etc etc! For
example, and ISP can allow login even with incorrect password, yet move
that client to a different ip range that is setup for redirection to an
internal portal to assist with resetting the password.
(&lt;a href="http://www.easyzonecorp.net/network/view.php?ID=1042"&gt;http://www.easyzonecorp.net/network/view.php?ID=1042&lt;/a&gt;). Or the link
from the start, they are using it so that when a datalimit is reached,
FreeRadius sends back a slower speed, i.e. throttling them once their
quota is used without disconnecting them! When you realise what power
RADIUS has, you understand why it's used by isp's and the like!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keywords to assist people in finding this information. Radius,
FreeRadius, Access-Reject, Reply-Message, CoovaChilli, ChilliSpot,
Hotspot, sql reply-message reject&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;ins&gt;
The original version of this document had "ok = reject" lines instead of reject
lines. This happened to work due a bug in Freeradius that has since been fixed.
The correct line is just a plain reject in the if statements.
&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[http://freeradius.1045715.n5.nabble.com/RESOLVED-customize-Post-Auth-Type-REJECT-td2779460.html&lt;br /&gt;
 ]: http://freeradius.1045715.n5.nabble.com/RESOLVED-customize-Post-Auth-Type-REJECT-td2779460.html&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Access-Reject"></category><category term="CoovaChili"></category><category term="FreeRadius"></category><category term="Hotspot"></category><category term="Reply-Message"></category></entry><entry><title>Brother HL-2140 Series Test/Information Page</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/03/brother-hl-2140-series-testinformation-page/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-03-18T15:37:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-03-18:2011/03/brother-hl-2140-series-testinformation-page/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Having many years ago had Brother printers that made it easy to print a
test or information page, it was good to finally find out how to do it
again. Of course, if you have the nice windows drivers, hidden in there
somewhere you can just click "Print Settings" and it will print out the
toner life, number of pages printed, etc etc. If you are using another
OS though, you won't always have that nice button.&lt;br /&gt;
Thankfully the trick is fairly simple. If your printer is on but
sleeping (The large "Go" button, the blue light one is dimmed) then just
press the button once to wake it up. Once awake, press the big blue
button 3 times, slow enough that it can register each press, fast enough
that you don't take all day doing it. You get the general idea. And out
will come a "Printer Settings" page, complete with a "bar" showing
remaining drum and toner life, total pages printed (even down to the
pages printed for each paper size), and error history and what page it
happened on. Apparently it even counts paper jams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I have to warn, that it doesn't always seem to get things right. I'm
sure I've had paper jams, yet it thinks I've had none. (Maybe I'm
remembering an older printer, I won't complain). It also says I've only
done about 1000 pages since getting the printer, now this I'm sure is
wrong as I printed 100's of pages for uni last semester.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless, it's probably a good idea to print one of these pages when
ever you change the toner, so you can get a good idea of how many pages
you are getting out of each toner!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;NB: This may or may not work on other Brother printers. It should work
for all the HL-2140 range (including the HL-2142 which is just the
HL-2140 branded exclusively for office works so no one can price match).&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="brother"></category><category term="hl2140"></category><category term="Printer"></category></entry><entry><title>GRASE Hotspot</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2010/12/grase-hotspot/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-12-14T21:55:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2010-12-14:2010/12/grase-hotspot/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;3 years in the making, and finally I am releasing the code for the GRASE
Hotspot. I've always planned on releasing the code, but had a lot things
I wanted done before the code was released, in particular making it easy
to install, and modular, as well as more secure than it previously was
(in particular the remote access).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For those that don't know much about the hotspot system I've been
working on, it's a simple captive portal system, that allows an
organisation/company to provide controlled internet access to users.
When a user tries to use a computer on the network (wireless or wired),
the first time they attempt to access a website, it redirects them to a
login screen. After a sucessful login they can then use the internet
until their time or data allowance is exhausted. The main part of the
GRASE Hotspot is the admin interface I have written. This provides a
simple interface for adding and managing users, as well as monitoring
usage and websites visited.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rest of the Hotspot system is what we call glue layers. This is the
process of connecting individual components together, in this case,
CoovaChilli, FreeRadius, MySQL, Squid and a few other components. Most
of the Hotspot solutions I researched required a lot of manual work
gluing the components together. All this hard work is taken care of
using the GRASE Hotspot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently the best way to get started using the system, is to download
the grase-repo deb package from
&lt;a href="http://hotspot.purewhite.id.au/apt/pool/main/g/grase-repo/"&gt;http://hotspot.purewhite.id.au/apt/pool/main/g/grase-repo/&lt;/a&gt; which will
setup the apt repository. Then head over to
&lt;a href="http://hotspot.purewhite.id.au/wiki/Documentation/Packages"&gt;http://hotspot.purewhite.id.au/wiki/Documentation/Packages&lt;/a&gt; to get an
idea of some of the other packages that can be installed to get started.
More information will appear over time at the main wiki page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some old screenshots (will be updated soon) and support forums are over
at &lt;a href="http://sf.net/projects/grase/"&gt;SourceForge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="CoovaChilli"></category><category term="FreeRadius"></category><category term="GRASE"></category><category term="GRASE Hotspot"></category><category term="Hotspot"></category></entry><entry><title>Asterisk Voip to Voip "Bridge" (Webcallback)</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2010/10/asterisk-voip-to-voip-bridge-webcallback/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-10-29T06:35:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2010-10-29:2010/10/asterisk-voip-to-voip-bridge-webcallback/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Call it what you like. Sip to Sip, VoIP to VoIP, VoIP Bridge, Callback,
Webcallback. The idea is to have a server somewhere call two SIP(VoIP)
devices and connect the 2 calls together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What's the point of it? Maybe you are stuck somewhere with a phone that
only accepts incoming calls, and you want to make cheap voip calls. Or
you are overseas, and it's cheaper to call from Australia to your
location that from your location to Australia. For example you may have
a payphone that accepts incoming calls but outgoing calls are expensive.
Or you just want to enjoy nice cheap VoIP rates but don't have any VoIP
hardware at your location, or poor dodgy internet, but have a mobile
phone or landline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What ever the reason, being able to have a VoIP call that connects to
your location, then calls another party is a great thing!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now before I go much further, if all you want is this ability to be
called, and then have your remote party called, &lt;a href="http://pennytel.com.au"&gt;PennyTel&lt;/a&gt; has this
Webcallback feature built in. Mynetfone doesn't, but if you can make
outgoing calls you can use their ANI callback feature (you call a
special number, your caller ID needs to not be blocked, and then you
hangup after it rings, then it calls you back and lets you make your
VoIP call). So, if you aren't going to be using this much, and don't
need lots of customisation or special features, just signup for PennyTel
and start using their Webcallback feature. Remember, you pay the cost of
2 calls using this feature, not 1. First, the cost to your number, then
the cost to whom you are calling. So if both parties are mobile phones,
then it certainly might not be cheap anymore. How ever, if your number
is a landline in australia, and so is the party you are calling, then
it'll cost a total of \$0.16 to make your call (on their Freedom Untimed
plan). This is pretty cheap compared to most normal telco's.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read on however, if you want the ability to use just about any VoIP
provider, and want to maybe use multiple VoIP providers and have heaps
of control over it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asterisk, the VoIP/PBX mega funky software, will turn a normal server
into a PBX/VoIP Gateway etc etc. When I first looked to a solution to
this issue a few years ago, I looked at the task of setting up Asterisk
and found it daunting, so gave up. PennyTel Webcallback essentially
delivered what I needed so I left it alone until now. I now have
Asterisk setup as a simple VoIP system that allows me to make 2 calls
(using multiple VoIP providers if I want) and join them together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why is it better than PennyTel Webcallback?&lt;br /&gt;
For me it's better because it can work out cheaper for me. PennyTel
callback is \$0.16 total (\$0.08 per each call to landline). However, if
I'm calling someone who is a MyNetFone customer, if  I was to call their
VoIP number from a MyNetFone VoIP account, the call would be free. And
if I'm on a MyNetFone monthly plan, then I could have a good number of
free landline calls each month. My optimal solution is currently
combining both MyNetFone and PennyTel. PennyTel to the normal landline,
\$0.08, and MyNetFone to the MyNetFone VoIP numbers, \$0.00. So it's a
total of \$0.08 for the whole call! So depending on your location, and
your destination number, and your VoIP provider plans, you can get your
calls cheaper than using PennyTel webcallback. And just the fact that
you can use this Callback method with just about any VoIP provider,
priceless!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So lets get onto the easy part, setting it all up. While at first this
can look daunting, in reality, it's very simple. This is all based on an
Ubuntu 10.04 box, using the CLI. Quick note before we start, what ever
machine you set this up on, needs to have enough bandwidth for 2 calls
at the same time. So if you are putting it on a home ADSL connection,
check you have enough up and down bandwidth for this. My server is
hosted out on the internet and has enough bandwidth. A big reason for me
setting this up is lack of a decent internet connection from my home to
be able to do normal VoIP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo apt-get install asterisk
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Yes,this does pull in a far few bits of software, some of which isn't
needed and I've not even poked at yet, but this is what we do to get
Asterisk installed. Easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the setup. You need to edit /etc/asterisk/sip.conf to add your VoIP
providers. Some providers give you the Asterisk details on their site,
many others are just a google away, generally on
http://www.voip-info.org/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So drop down to the bottom of the [general] section in
/etc/asterisk/sip.conf and add in a register line for each VoIP
provider. Mine is in the following format. You can see that the username
is repeated a few times on the mynetfone one. It can be different for
other providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="na"&gt;register&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;gt; username@sip01.mynetfone.com.au:password:username@sip01.mynetfone.com.au/username&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="na"&gt;register&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;gt; 888xxxxxxx:secret@sip.pennytel.com/888xxxxxxx&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now drop to the bottom of the /etc/asterisk/sip.conf file, and add in
your "trunks" for the VoIP providers. In my situation, I don't want
incoming calls (as then they need to be routed), so I just have the
outgoing trunks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;[mynetfone-out]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;disallow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;all&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;allow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;alaw&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;allow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;ulaw&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;allow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;ilbc&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;allow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;g729&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;allow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;gsm&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;allow&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;g723&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;authname&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;09xxxxxx&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;canreinvite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;no&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;dtmfmode&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;rfc2833&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;fromuser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;09xxxxxx&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;host&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;sip01.mynetfone.com.au&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;insecure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;very&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;nat&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;no&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;pedantic&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;no&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;qualify&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;yes&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;secret&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;password&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;friend&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;defaultuser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;09xxxxxx&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;[pennytel-out]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;type&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;friend&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;host&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;sip.pennytel.com&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;fromuser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;888xxxxxxx&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;defaultuser&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;888xxxxxxx&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;secret&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;password&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;canreinvite&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;no&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;insecure&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;invite&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Again, these can look different. A bit of googling around should help,
or if you work from the above you should be able to work out the
settings for your own provider. Note, username is no more in newer
Asterisk versions, it's now defaultuser, so you may need to change what
you find on the net.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have a look in /etc/asterisk/manager.conf, you'll see you need to create
a file in /etc/asterisk/manager.d/ to add a user. You may wish to do
this so you can use the astman tool later, which helps with
disconnecting calls and monitoring things. (You can do this through the
asterisk cli, how ever it may be a bit harder).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The format of the file you create is as follows.
/etc/asterisk/manager.d/somename.conf&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;[username]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;secret&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;password&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;read&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;system,call,log,verbose,command,agent,user,config&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;write&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="s"&gt;system,call.log,verbose,command,agent,user,config&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This username and password isn't related to your VPS at all, it's what
you'll use when logging in with Astman or other tools.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we get to the bit we've been waiting for, setting it up to connect 2
calls.&lt;br /&gt;
Edit /etc/asterisk/extensions.conf. Comment out the include =&gt; demo
line from the [default] section. There is a section in the [default]
that should sort out Hangup/Busy detection and the likes, so the
extensions we are adding can be very simple, however, you can customise
these very easily to do more than just connect the 2 calls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="k"&gt;[DialOutMyNetFone]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;exten&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;gt; _0X.,1,Dial(SIP/mynetfone-out/${EXTEN})&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class="k"&gt;[DialOutPennyTel]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="na"&gt;exten&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="s"&gt;&amp;gt; _0X.,1,Dial(SIP/pennytel-out/${EXTEN})&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;And we are done. Everything should be setup now. The default install of
Asterisk has autoloading on in /etc/asterisk/modules.conf so the rest
should just work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all those edits, restart asterisk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;sudo /etc/init.d/asterisk restart
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now we create our call file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="err"&gt;Channel:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;SIP/pennytel-out/YOURNUMBER&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="err"&gt;Context:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;DialOutMyNetFone&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="err"&gt;Extension:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;WHOTOCALLNUMBER&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="err"&gt;Priority:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class="err"&gt;Archive:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="err"&gt;Yes&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Very simple file. The Channel line is what calls you, so replace
pennytel-out with the trunk you wish to use to call you. (It can be the
same as the trunk used later on, or different. In this example, it's
different as I want the cheap call to my landline, and the free call to
a mynetfone number). The Context is the extension name that we defined
in /etc/asterisk/extensions.conf, and the Extension is the number that
you wish to call. Both for YOURNUMBER and WHOTOCALLNUMBER you need to
know the format your VoIP provider uses. Some will allow just a
localised version, for example in australia I can just dial 075xxxxxx or
040 123 4567, and MyNetFone understands them. Some other VoIP providers
might need 6175xxxxxx instead. Dialing internation, some just need the
country code, others need a prefix like 0011, etc etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to actually place the call. There are a number of methods of doing
this, the end result needs to be a call file placed in the
/var/spool/asterisk/outgoing directory, owned by the asterisk user, and
placed in a way that asterisk can't start reading it before the file is
all there. For this reason, the mv command is recommended and I'll
demonstrate. (I first copy the file so I can keep a number of pre setup
files stored).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;cp preset1.call call123.call
sudo chown asterisk call123.call
sudo mv call123.call /var/spool/asterisk/outgoing/
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;As soon as the file hits that directory, asterisk reads it and executes
it. If everything goes right, within 10 seconds your phone should start
ringing. Pick it up, it'll then start ringing the other party, finally,
when they pickup you can start talking! Done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes the hangup detection doesn't work properly. I've not yet
worked out why or how to fix it, I believe there are a number of things
to tweak regarding this. What I currently do is run 'astman localhost'
(from the machine running asterisk), login with the details we setup
earlier, and I can think select the call and press hangup if it doesn't
hangup correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more details about Call files, check out
&lt;a href="http://www.voip-info.org/wiki/view/Asterisk+auto-dial+out"&gt;http://www.voip-info.org/wiki/view/Asterisk+auto-dial+out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, it's not always practical to ssh into your server just to
make a phone call. I'll leave the task of setting up other methods of
creating and moving the call files to the reader. Please though, don't
give your web server user full sudo access without a password! I'd
recommend ether a database with a cron runner script (running as the
asterisk user), or something similar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last things. Check your firewall. You'll need to open some RTP ports and
some SIP ports. A google will reveal more. Try to limit what you open
though, I've not given any instructions for securing asterisk in this
post, that also is for your further reading.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="asterisk"></category><category term="bridge"></category><category term="callback"></category><category term="sip"></category><category term="sip to sip"></category><category term="voip"></category><category term="voip to voip"></category><category term="webcallback"></category></entry><entry><title>Internet Reception</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2010/10/internet-reception/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-10-27T10:32:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2010-10-27:2010/10/internet-reception/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/images/2010/10/IMAG0061.jpg"&gt;&lt;img alt="Modem Reception" src="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/images/2010/10/IMAG0061-179x300.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt; So we finally got our modem a few weeks back. A 3G9WB, also
known as a 3G9WT (Telstra Branding) or a 7.2 Home Gateway. Really, it's
just a Netcomm router with a Sierra mobile module inside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's unlocked, but we still can only get Telstra NextG, although with a
Yagi we might be able to get Optus 3G. However, even Telstra NextG is
dodgy, showing as "Low" signal strength, or 2 bars out of 5. Often it'll
just stop because the signal is too low. And 2G (EDGE) isn't any better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So today we needed to download some video editing software, thought we
give &lt;a href="http://www.openshotvideo.com/" title="OpenShot Video Editor"&gt;OpenShot&lt;/a&gt; a try instead of Cinelerra. Hoping for something a
little simpler for basic editing. The download started off with an ETA
of 30mins, and then the speed just kept dropping. Soon our ETA was 4
hours. I'd had enough, so I opened the window, removed the flyscreen and
climbed onto the window sill. I then carefully wedged the modem into the
louvers. Still only a low signal, but success! The download was finished
in 3minutes! I might actually be able to upload my assignment quickly
with the modem here (when the submission link is fixed up).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, until we get an external antenna, we'll just have to use an external
modem! :-P&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="3g9wb"></category><category term="modem"></category><category term="nextg"></category></entry><entry><title>Code</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2010/09/code/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-09-09T18:23:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2010-09-09:2010/09/code/</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Home</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2010/09/home/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-09-09T18:23:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2010-09-09:2010/09/home/</id><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title>Handbrake Encoding Cluster</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2010/09/handbrake-encoding-cluster/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2010-09-09T18:18:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2010-09-09:2010/09/handbrake-encoding-cluster/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Recently I've been given the task of putting a DVD collection on to the
computer (for backup purposes, so that the originals can be locked away
and not damaged by little hands). Having used &lt;a href="http://handbrake.fr"&gt;Handbrake&lt;/a&gt; before to
convert DVD's to H.264 videos, I figured I'd be able to use it again.
But for such a large task, it makes sense to have many computers doing
the encoding. Unlike dvd::rip, Handbrake doesn't have a distributed
cluster feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found a possible solution in the Handbrake Forums, using ppss and some
scripts. &lt;a href="http://forum.handbrake.fr/viewtopic.php?f=6&amp;amp;t=17504"&gt;http://forum.handbrake.fr/viewtopic.php?f=6&amp;amp;t=17504&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, I wasn't able to get PPSS working how I wanted (or at
all). However, it did provide me with a transcode bash script that
assisted with getting the HandbrakeCLI options right, in particular
splitting TV episodes into individual episodes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I continued looking for ways to do this, knowing I'd previously used
some clustering script many years ago, and finally found &lt;a href="http://gearman.org/"&gt;gearman&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
At first glace, gearman seems to be perfect, except digging deeper you
discover it's designed to be called from within applications and not so
much as a command line "queue". Thankfully I discovered a &lt;a href="http://stefaanlippens.net/gearman_setting_worker_process_arguments_through_xargs"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;
explaining how to make gearman more command line friendly using xargs.
(Which also helped me finally understand how xargs work!) So with a bit
of scripting I had myself a number of small shell scripts, a gearmand
server, and a working cluster.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, I setup some NFS mounts on all the computers involved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;mkdir /mnt/DVD_rip
&lt;span class="nv"&gt;$ &lt;/span&gt;mkdir /mnt/DVD_encode
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;For me, I had 2 mounts as I wanted the DVD_rip folder to be on a local
computer, and the DVD_encode folder to be on a server that all the
finished files needed to be on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I then created a simple &lt;a href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/code/handbrake-cluster/rip"&gt;bash script&lt;/a&gt; for ripping the disks (with
error handling). I can run this script in the /mnt/DVD_rip folder, give
it one argument (the DVD name) and it'll rip the disk and attempt to
retry any sectors that have errors. The 'lsdvd' is so that css keys are
loaded so you can read encrypted DVD's. You can also stop and restart
the ripping process at any time without loosing what has been ripped
successfully. NB: It doesn't remove the CSS encryption so you will need
libdvdcss on all computers doing encoding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;lsdvd /dev/sr0 &amp;gt; /dev/null &amp;amp; ddrescue -r 1 /dev/sr0 &amp;quot;$1.iso&amp;quot; &amp;quot;$1.log&amp;quot;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;My next script (&lt;a href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/code/handbrake-cluster/submitjob.sh"&gt;submitjob.sh&lt;/a&gt;) is another 1 liner, it submits the job
to gearmand. It simply takes the name of the file to encode (iso or a
video file) and optionally an attribute that ether tells our transcoding
script to encode all the titles (split episodes) or which title to
encode. Without this attribute it will scan for the longest title and
only encode that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My next script (&lt;a href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/code/handbrake-cluster/startworker.sh"&gt;startworker.sh&lt;/a&gt;) starts the gearman worker processes.
I run it on each machine in the cluster that I want processing videos. I
usually run it in a screen session as when it's encoding it outputs some
information through this script, the rest goes into log files. NB: The
script has the hostname of the gearmand server in it as does the
&lt;a href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/code/handbrake-cluster/submitjob.sh"&gt;submitjob.sh&lt;/a&gt; script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our last script (&lt;a href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/code/handbrake-cluster/transcode2mkv.sh"&gt;transcode2mkv.sh&lt;/a&gt;) is the actually transcoding
script. This is what the gearman worker calls to do the encoding. I got
this script from the method that uses PPSS at
&lt;a href="http://forum.handbrake.fr/viewtopic.php?f=6&amp;amp;t=17504"&gt;http://forum.handbrake.fr/viewtopic.php?f=6&amp;amp;t=17504&lt;/a&gt;. I then modified
it to encode to mkv files instead of mp4, and I changed some of the
default encoding options, as well as how it handled the titles (i.e.
selecting all, or individual ones), and how it handled selection of
audio and subtitle tracks (it selected them all, I wanted it to just
select the English audio, and all the subtitles). I also added logging
so that it would update a cluster log when it started and stopped
encoding (with timestamps), and to log the progress output to one
logfile, and the verbose information to another logfile (so I could
easily tail the logfile to get the current progress).&lt;br /&gt;
Initially for doing TV episodes, this script would select all the
titles and encode each one to it's own file. I changed it to just select
the 4 I wanted, and then later changed it so I could select individual
titles. The reason I changed to selecting individual titles was that
some of my encoding machines are faster than others, this way I didn't
have 3 machines sitting idle while one machine was still on the first
title of the disk, instead they each took a title and the disk was
processed a lot quicker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the files can be found at
&lt;a href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/code/handbrake-cluster"&gt;http://tim.purewhite.id.au/code/handbrake-cluster&lt;/a&gt; or checked out with
bzr.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;bzr branch http://tim.purewhite.id.au/code/handbrake-cluster/
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="bzr"></category><category term="cluster"></category><category term="code"></category><category term="distributed"></category><category term="encode"></category><category term="encoding"></category><category term="gearman"></category><category term="handbrake"></category><category term="handbrakecli"></category><category term="script"></category><category term="transcode"></category></entry></feed>