<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Technically Tim - Blog, projectX</title><link href="//tim.purewhite.id.au/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="//tim.purewhite.id.au/feeds/blog-projectx.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>//tim.purewhite.id.au/</id><updated>2011-08-22T16:53:00+10:00</updated><entry><title>Day 6</title><link href="//tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/08/day-6/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-08-22T16:53:00+10:00</published><updated>2011-08-22T16:53:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-08-22:/2011/08/day-6/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;So not much has happened over the weekend due to it being very busy.
Today the mini-DVI to HDMI adapter arrived, so I could finally "dock"
the Macbook at my desk. After "docking" it with my monitor, keyboard and
mouse, it suddenly feels less like a laptop and more like …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So not much has happened over the weekend due to it being very busy.
Today the mini-DVI to HDMI adapter arrived, so I could finally "dock"
the Macbook at my desk. After "docking" it with my monitor, keyboard and
mouse, it suddenly feels less like a laptop and more like a desktop!
More screen realestate is a big bonus. But being able to just pick it
up, pull out a few cables and take it with me, tether it to my mobile
via wifi and work on the go, just makes such a difference to having a
separate desktop and laptop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I already used a password manager under Linux, I wanted an
application that was compatible with my existing password database.
Thankfully, Password Gorilla runs on OS X, and all the other platforms,
and reads the same password database as pwsafe does. So while I was out
today, I finally migrated a number of machine passwords into a secure
"safe". The GUI is rather nice on the Mac, so I may considering using it
under Linux too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've also installed Qumana which will allow me to blog without using a
browser. This is something I did many moons ago, and so thought I'd try
it again for this Project as it assists in making me use the Mac for the
whole time, rather than using interfaces/apps/things that I am already
comfortable with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I have a few uni assignments due this week, I probably won't spend
much time working on the project. And unfortunately, at least for one of
the assignments, I will have to use my Linux machine to complete it due
to some tools that aren't available for Mac. I have contemplated
installing Linux on the Mac, but for now figure that the time spent
doing that is better spent on the assignments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, while setting in a shopping centre working today, some
random walked past and said something like "Mac's are nice aren't they?"
So for all those who want people to stop and talk to you, get a Mac!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think I have gotten this Mac to the point that it's now very usable
for me. I've installed enough apps to get me going, and I'm forcing
myself to learn all the Mac shortcuts. Now I'll use it for all my
Assignments this week as much as possible, and I think by the end of the
week, I'll probably be using my Linux machine via VNC on my Mac!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;&lt;em&gt;Powered by&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="http://www.qumana.com/"&gt;Qumana&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Day 3</title><link href="//tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/08/day-3/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2011-08-19T12:15:00+10:00</published><updated>2011-08-19T12:15:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-08-19:/2011/08/day-3/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've decided to blog this journey of learning and challenge. I am
developing a mobile app, initially for iOS and eventually for Android. I
have given myself an initial 60 days to get it done, 60 days from
getting the equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being an iOS app, I required an Apple Mac …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I've decided to blog this journey of learning and challenge. I am
developing a mobile app, initially for iOS and eventually for Android. I
have given myself an initial 60 days to get it done, 60 days from
getting the equipment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being an iOS app, I required an Apple Mac computer to run the required
development tools. Tuesday afternoon an iPhone 3GS and a MacBook
arrived, curtsey of a friend of Jun's. First thing I needed to do was
download the Lion update, so I could run XCode 4.1. This started Tuesday
evening and was finished by Wednesday morning (Day 1). I then prepared a
USB Drive to boot the installer from, and went and purchased a new
laptop HDD to upgrade the MacBook. By lunch time I'd fitted the new
500Gb HDD and the OS X Lion install was finished. Now started the 6-8hr
download of XCode. Meanwhile I spent some time getting aquainted with
this MacBook and OS X. No, I'm not converted like some people have been
asking, however it probably will be my main computer for the next 60 odd
days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday (day 2) I wrote a Hello World app in XCode for iOS. It was
copied straight from a tutorial on the net, and I quickly discovered
that Apple wants \$99 from me to be able to even test it on my iPhone!
Come on Apple, you already get the money for the MacBook, the iPhone,
and now you want more money just so we can test apps on our OWN
devices!?!? Eventually we'll need to fork out this money so we can sign
our apps and put them on the App Store. For now though, I think I'll
just jailbreak for testing purposes.&lt;br&gt;
I've continued getting acquainted with the MacBook. It now runs Firefox
and Thunderbird, iCal is 2 way syncing my calendar. Clementine has
become my music player (iTunes, no thanks), LibreOffice is installed.
TextWrangler may become my other code editor if it is good enough.
Dropbox is setup for syncing between my MacBook and certain folders on
my main computer. So far, it's been nice using this computer, however
it's certainly not better than similar hardware running Linux. For a
start, it took me a long time to get network shares with our NAS working
well, even though it supports AFP. Eventually it was easier to just
setup NFS. I'm getting used to all the keyboard shortcuts, which once
learned certainly speed up some navigation. Annoyingly, there have been
some things where a keyboard doesn't work and you have to use a mouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding code, it looks like I'll probably use Git for the SCM as its
built in to XCode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thats all for Day 3 so far. I need to get some uni work done and we have
a busy weekend. I look forward to next week when I'll have to make this
iPhone run my apps!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Apple"></category><category term="Development"></category><category term="iOS"></category><category term="iPhone"></category><category term="Mac"></category><category term="MacBook"></category><category term="OS X"></category><category term="project"></category><category term="XCode"></category></entry></feed>