<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Technically Tim</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/feeds/blog.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://tim.purewhite.id.au/</id><updated>2013-05-18T17:18:00+10:00</updated><entry><title>"Windows" is full of bloat</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2013/05/windows-is-full-of-bloat/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-18T17:18:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2013-05-18:2013/05/windows-is-full-of-bloat/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;It's been some time since I've had to do some work on a Windows
computer, in particular lots of software installs and uninstalls to
cleanup a slow computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now before you jump the gun, I'm not talking about Windows the operating
system being full of bloat, although it may be. I'm also not talking
about the bloat that comes installed on OEM installs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I am talking about, is how so much third party free windows
software is full of bloat. Just about every installer now wants to
install another piece of software with the piece you downloaded, ether a
toolbar or another "great" piece of software they recommend to you. And
then when you uninstall a piece of software, just about every piece of
software then insist on opening a webpage saying how sorry they are that
you uninstalled the software and would you please do this 5 minute
survey telling them why blah blah blah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And even my favourite antivirus Avast has started doing it. First, the
installer has jumped from 20Mb a few years ago to over 100Mb now. And
now when you install it, if you aren't watching out it'll try and
install Google Drive, and once it is installed it keeps popping up
asking you to install the great security extension for chrome, blah blah
blah.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What ever happened to nice free software that wasn't packed full of
bloat, and that let you install and uninstall just that software that
you asked for without trying to push other software on you? I'll happily
keep my Linux world, where software does what you ask, and nothing more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And if you live in the Windows world, seriously, I think it's well past
time to get out, but you can still get out now!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="bloat"></category><category term="windows"></category></entry><entry><title>When did 'Linux' start moving away from it's simplicity?</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2012/05/when-did-linux-start-moving-away-from-its-simplicity/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2012-05-08T19:46:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2012-05-08:2012/05/when-did-linux-start-moving-away-from-its-simplicity/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Today I had the joy of trying to change a users desktop environment from
Gnome, to Cinnamon, via ssh. At first I thought it would be easy, change
the default desktop environment in lightdm.conf and restart. Fail. Ok,
so where is a users desktop environment preference stored? .dmrc, or at
least I thought so. I even logged in with a brand new user and confirmed
that it saved the users desktop preference in \~/.dmrc. Except, if I
changed .dmrc for a user, it just got overwritten with the old contents
at their next automatic login. (Remember, ssh, so can't use the gui to
change what was selected in the lightdm login screen).&lt;br /&gt;
Wha?!!? Surely not a dconf/gconf setting somewhere. Search search
search. Still no luck. Eventually I discover a service called
"AccountsService" or something along that name. It stores the users
".dmrc" contents in /var/lib/AccountsService/users/ with a file for each
user, which believe it or not, can't be changed by the user! Arg! (And I
believe you need to kill accountsservice to be able to change the
contents of the file and have it actually honored, I tried just changing
it, but ended up changing it then rebooting to get it to work)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is stupidity! Have a daemon, that one of it's tasks is to tell the
"display manager" what the users preferred desktop environment
preference is, that stores it in a place the user can't change, without
talking to the daemon! Oh, and write the contents of that file out to
.dmrc at login, but don't bother reading from that file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing some more digging, AccountService is for querying and manipulating
user account information via D-Bus, essentially replacing the useradd,
usermod and userdel commands. I can't find a "homepage" for it, the
homepage listed is it's source code repo.
(&lt;a href="http://cgit.freedesktop.org/accountsservice/"&gt;http://cgit.freedesktop.org/accountsservice/&lt;/a&gt;)  (NB: Some more digging
finds this &lt;a href="http://www.freedesktop.org/wiki/Software/AccountsService"&gt;http://www.freedesktop.org/wiki/Software/AccountsService&lt;/a&gt; as
the homepage)&lt;br /&gt;
I personally don't mind D-Bus, it services its purposes, but here is an
instance where it looks like someone has gone to the trouble of writing
a piece of code, to complicate some that use to be a simple stat/open of
a file, that the user was in total control of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the record, lightdm will work without AccountsService, and I believe
then it will honor \~/.dmrc&lt;br /&gt;
Also, accountsservice isn't in Debian stable, but is in Debian testing,
and gdm3 and gnome depend on it. (So in other words Gnome3 depends on
it)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I just don't understand why we need to reinvent the wheel, take
something that is so simple (and fits in the Unix "philosophies" of
everything is a file, and that file formats should be simple text based)
and turn it into something that user no longer has control over, for
something that sets their preference!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Read
[http://blog.ngas.ch/archives/2011/12/13/the_destructive_desktop__mdash_linux_in_trouble/index.html][]for
some more thoughts on dbus.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="nl"&gt;http:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="c1"&gt;//blog.ngas.ch/archives/2011/12/13/the_destructive_desktop__mdash_linux_in_trouble/index.html%20&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</summary><category term="accountservice"></category><category term="accountsservice"></category><category term="dbus"></category><category term="Gnome3"></category><category term="Linux"></category><category term="simplicity"></category><category term="unix"></category></entry><entry><title>Google+ (Google's Social Network)</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/07/google-googles-social-network/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-07-15T10:57:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-07-15:2011/07/google-googles-social-network/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;By now you should have heard about Google+. You may have some idea of
what it is, or you may have none, so hopefully I can answer some of your
questions and help you get started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Firstly, Google+ is Google's latest entry into social networking.
Already it looks much better than Buzz or Wave. What I like about it
already is that the interface is clean and simple, and most importantly
it is very easy to control your privacy settings. Now Facebook does have
a similar feature, but it is extremely difficult to use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Circles. You simple assign your "friends" to different circles, they can
be in more than one. Then, you can share a post/photo/video etc with
different circles, individual people, or the public. (There is also an
extended circles which I believe shares it with people in your circles,
and people in their circles). Want to let the world know about your new
baby, simply post it public! (Like twitter). Want to post how you are
having a dodgy day but only want your friends to know, and not your
boss, just post it to your friends circle and make sure you boss is in
your work circle. Want to share some good news with family and few close
friends, post it to your family circle and then add the extra friends in
as well!&lt;br /&gt;
Circles make it very simple to control who see's what on your Google+
profile. Given the security scares of facebook stalkers and the like,
it's good to know you have total control over who see's what.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently there are no Google+ games or apps. However for me that's a
bonus. I'm sick of all these status updates of "I just completed level
235 of bubble popping game...." and lots of other meaningless things
like that. I don't mind people playing games, but I don't want to hear
about it! What Google+ offers you out of the box though, is an amazing
tool for social network communications that will allow you to easily
keep in contact with people from all areas of your life, without getting
cluttered down in the mechanisms of the communications. Huddles allow
you to create a group of people for discussing something, like a group
assignment, complete with group video chat (which arrived before
Facebook announce the Skype Video partnership).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm hoping that you have read this far and are at least interested in
trying Google+. For many people, until all your friends are there, you
aren't going to move. In fact, unless you are sick of the bloat of
facebook, you probably have very little incentive to move unless you
have privacy concerns with facebook. However I urge to to consider this,
someone has to take the first steps so that others will follow. And if
you need a good reason to take those first steps, I believe the privacy
issues of facebook should be enough for anyone to think twice about
facebook. And, if Google+ does flop, or you want to run away from it,
all the stuff you put on it is yours, there is a nice easy way to
download all your photos and other things on Google+ so you aren't
locked in!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now here is the hard part, Google+ is still currently invite only as
it's still in it's "trial" stages while they work out bugs. So below is
a form that you can put your name and email address in, and a short note
if you desire, and I'll invite you to Google+. Due to the demand for
invites, there are 2 things we do to try and get you in. First we send
you an invite, then we share a post with you. You'll get 2 emails, try
the invite one first, which should have a red button to "Learn more
about Google+" which will hopefully take you to the signin page to
create your profile. If that fails, the second email will have a link to
"View or Comment on Blah Blahs Post". This link will also hopefully take
you to a page where you can fill out your public profile and then sign
in to Google+.&lt;br /&gt;
Both methods work at different times, so if it doesn't work for you
immediately, please wait an hour and try again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I promise to not do anything with your email address other than invite
you to Google+. Please be patient as I need to manually invite each
person unless I can work out some way to automate this. I am happy to
invite people I don't know, however please don't be offended if you
don't end up in my circles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Form removed as invites no longer needed)&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="facebook"></category><category term="google+"></category><category term="googleplus"></category><category term="invites"></category><category term="social network"></category></entry><entry><title>"The Ultimate Steal" is right</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/06/the-ultimate-steal-is-right/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-06-02T14:17:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-06-02:2011/06/the-ultimate-steal-is-right/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Microsoft's student "Its not stealing" campaign is supposed to make it
easy for students to afford Microsoft products so they don't need to
pirate them (and steal them). That's fine as long as it works and
Microsoft don't steal from us!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twice I've now attempted to place an order with the online system, twice
the order has been denied however the pre-authorisation on my credit
card means I'm now \$300 "out of pocket" until the transactions are
reversed in the next 5 business days. I've called my bank (before trying
to place the order the second time) to ensure that there wasn't a
problem with my account or the credit card. No problem from the banks
end, it should have gone through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fittingly the email I got from them after complaining comes from "The
Ultimate Steal AU". We'll it sure is the ultimate steal, lets take your
money and give you nothing. And yes, I know I get the money back, but
it's my time and effort I'm wasting, and if I needed that money to pay a
bill, it's not there. Experiences like this sure make me want to buy
from Micro\$oft!! Oh, and if I was rich and had lots of money in my
account, each time I hit submit to attempt again (like the text
suggests) would be another \$150 pre-authorisation without success. Not
a great payment system if you ask me, no safety limits to prevent you
from trying again and again. You could easily have a few thousand
dollars in pre-auth as you keep checking the details, sure they are
correct, you hit submit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully they can fix it faster than the amount of time I spent on hold
just to be told they can't do anything!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="digital river"></category><category term="micro$oft"></category><category term="microsoft"></category><category term="steal"></category></entry><entry><title>What it takes to keep things running. (How to reduce comment/wiki spam)</title><link href="http://tim.purewhite.id.au/2011/04/what-it-takes-to-keep-things-running-how-to-reduce-commentwiki-spam/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2011-04-05T22:13:00+10:00</updated><author><name>Tim White</name></author><id>tag:tim.purewhite.id.au,2011-04-05:2011/04/what-it-takes-to-keep-things-running-how-to-reduce-commentwiki-spam/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I recently pushed out a new version of the &lt;a href="http://hotspot.purewhite.id.au/"&gt;GRASE Hotspot&lt;/a&gt;. I spent
lots of time working on rewriting the splash/welcome page, and login
forms so that they would work even with javascript disabled, and allow
you to force it into the non javascript version if you are having
problems (so browsers like Safari can be used). However, recently I've
spent a lot of time just doing maintenance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The maintenance started when again I spent lots of time cleaning up spam
on the wiki, this was after enabling ReCAPTCHA. I decided it wasn't
practical to keep cleaning up the wiki, and seeing as I was the only one
contributing to it, it made more sense migrating it to a Wordpress site.
After the migration was done, I quickly started getting comment spam on
the new site!! Thankfully, Akismet blocks comment spam, but the volume
of spam coming in was enormous! A peek into the server logs showed that
the same ip's that were publishing spam in the wiki, would try to get
post to the missing wiki, find it missing and discover the wordpress
site and immediately try to post comment spam! It was time to reduce the
load on the server if possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After some research, I implemented some basic .htaccess rules that would
block some of the spam even getting processed. But why couldn't I find a
simple DNSBL for Apache? Turns out the right googling will find
libapache2-mod-spamhaus, which does what we need. But unlike email spam,
it seems comment/wiki spammers aren't in the DNSBL's as much as email
spammers. Thankfully, libapache2-mod-spamhaus was now dropping about
half the spamming connections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some more research turned up &lt;a href="%20http://www.projecthoneypot.org?rf=93412" title="Project Honey Pot"&gt;Project Honey Pot&lt;/a&gt; which is aimed more
at the comment spammers and address harvesters. A quick check of the ip
database they maintain revealed that most of the remaining comment
spammer ips that were hitting my site were in their database!
Unfortunately, the mod_httpbl module for Apache isn't in a nice
repository anywhere, and hasn't been touched for awhile, so setup wasn't
as easy. I found &lt;a href="http://repel.in-progress.com/"&gt;Repel&lt;/a&gt; which is a simple Python program that you use
with mod_rewrite (and RewriteMap's). It's not so easy to setup, mainly
due to the instructions being a little unclear, but also because the
rewrite rules that use Repel can be very tricky. The documentation was
good for just blocking, however I figured if I was going to use Project
Honey Pot, I should contribute too, so I setup a honeypot on the site
and then had fun and games with rewrite rules. Eventually though, I got
it all setup. Now if you are thinking of setting this up yourself, it's
probably a lot easier using the &lt;a href="http://wordpress.org/extend/plugins/httpbl/" title="Wordpress Http:bl Plugin"&gt;Wordpress Plugin&lt;/a&gt; which I've since
setup on another site I assist with. While this will block the spammers,
or direct them to a honeypot, it may have slightly more load than Repel.
This is because Repel is a little python program, that apache already
has running, and just passes the ipaddress to and waits for a reply. The
wordpress plugin solution requires Apache to fire up PHP, which then
fires up Wordpress, which then loads the plugin which finally gets the
ipaddress, does the DNS lookup and then goes from there. I've done no
testing, but logically Repel would appear to use less resources, but you
are welcome to prove me wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On top of all that maintenance, I also had some mail servers receiving
spam, which should have been blocked. Some more tweaks and changes, and
another influx of spam is now not getting past the gate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lastly, some advice. Password advice. In particular because I heard an
"expert" on the ABC radio recently giving some poor advice. Get yourself
a strong password, with letters and numbers, maybe some capital letters
as well as lowercase, and decent length, at least 8 characters long. Now
use that password for one place, and only one place, maybe your email
account. Now find another one, just as strong, use that for your next
account, maybe facebook. Reusing passwords is a big No No, as an
important CEO recently discovered.&lt;br /&gt;
I can hear you already, moaning and groaning. It's so hard to remember
one really strong password, how can you remember more than one? Well
this is the easy part. You use a formula. I've started using
&lt;a href="https://www.pwdhash.com/" title="PwdHash"&gt;PwdHash&lt;/a&gt;, developed by Standford University. It simply takes the
domain name of the site you are generating the password, and your master
password, and creates you a "hash" that you use as your password for
that site. So for example, if my master password was
'thecatsatonthemat', my facebook password would be
'F58VFRH8eUejfcIs9UA'. This will let you create strong unique passwords
for each account, then if one of your accounts is broken into and the
password somehow discovered, your other accounts are safe. Of course, if
your email account gets broken into, a lot of other accounts are not
safe as the hacker can then just reset your passwords by using the "Lost
Password" feature many sites provide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do decide to use PwdHash, you can install a firefox extension
that assist, or you can use it directly on the site (as it uses
Javascript, your password never leaves the computer, you can even save
the page and use it offline). I found a little python script that does
it for me, which I have on my server and my machine, so I can create my
pwdhash's even when I don't have a browser handy. Of course, there is
nothing preventing you having multiple master passwords ether, just to
make it even more secure!&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="password"></category><category term="project honey pot"></category><category term="pwdhash"></category><category term="security"></category><category term="spam"></category></entry></feed>